本字幕由志愿者义务贡献，采用许可协议
知识共享 署名-非商业性使用-相同方式共享 3.0 美国
>> Welcome to Stanford CS193, winter quarter of 2017.
欢迎参加 2017 年冬季学期斯坦福 CS193P 课程
Today I'm going to continue that demo that we started last
I'm really just going to enhance it to be multiple MVC
我将把它提升为多个MVC
time.
时间。
again, it gives you a chance to see it all happen again.
再一次，它给你一个机会，让你看到它再次发生。
And I'm gonna be going very quickly for
我很快就会讲
doing that because we already did that in the last demo, so
因为我们在上次的演示中已经做过了
and you did it on your homework,
你做作业的时候，
so hopefully it's really, really comfortable.
希望它非常非常舒服。
Now we're going to dive back into the slides and
现在我们要回到幻灯片
solve a problem that we're going to have with our app,
解决了我们的应用程序的问题，
which is that it's really slow.
它的速度很慢。
And not only really slow, but it blocks our user interface
不仅很慢，而且还会阻塞我们的用户界面
so that the user thinks the app is probably dead and
用户认为这款应用可能已经死了
needs to be killed or something.
需要被杀。
And we're gonna fix that with multithreading, so
我们将用多线程解决这个问题
I'm gonna talk a little about how we do multithreading.
我将简单介绍一下我们是如何多线程的。
I'll go back to the demo,
回到demo，
we'll fix it with multithreading.
我们将用多线程修复它。
I'm gonna show you a couple other cool things to do.
我将给你们展示一些其他很酷的事情。
And then we're gonna come back to the slides and
然后我们会回到幻灯片
I'm gonna talk about text field, which is a little bit
我要讲一下文本框，这有点
of a random topic, but I have to fit it in somewhere.
一个随机的话题，但我必须把它放在某个地方。
And if I have a little time at the end, which I doubt I will,
如果我最后有一点时间，我怀疑我会，
but if I have time at the end, I'll actually get started on
但如果我有时间的话，我会开始的
table view, which is gonna be our big topic for Wednesday.
表格视图，这将是我们周三的大话题。
A very important topic, and
一个非常重要的话题
it's what your next assignment is gonna be about.
这是你的下一个任务。
Sorry, your next assignment has multi-threading as well,
抱歉，下一个作业也有多线程，
of course, but it's mostly a table view assignment, so
当然，但这主要是一个表视图赋值
that's what we're gonna do today.
这就是我们今天要做的。
So let's jump right back into our demo from last time.
让我们回到上次的演示。
You remember that it looked like this, so
你记得它看起来是这样的
here it is running.
这是跑步。
And this was a nice little image viewing application so
这是一个很好的图像浏览应用程序
far, and we can zoom in and out, and pan around, and
我们可以放大，缩小，平移
all that.
这一切。
And in fact, in building this application,
实际上，在构建这个应用程序时，
I've built this nice generic ImageViewController.
我构建了一个很好的通用ImageViewController。
It's a reusable MVC, just like in your assignment,
这是一个可重用的MVC，就像你的作业一样，
you built a reusable graphing view controller, well,
你建立了一个可复用的图形视图控制器，
I've built a generic MVC that will show an image and
我已经构建了一个通用的MVC，它将显示一个图像和
let you zoom in on it and pan around, so, that's kinda cool.
让你放大它，平移一下，这很酷。
Hopefully you're gaining an appreciation for
希望你在欣赏
good API design, and how important good API design and
良好的API设计，以及良好的API设计和
reusable componentry is to building good architecture in
可重用组件是构建良好的体系结构
general, so hopefully, you're seeing that.
一般，希望你们能看到。
I mean, these are very simple applications that we're
我的意思是，这些都是非常简单的应用
writing, so it's hard to see.
写作，很难看到。
But when you start building a huge app and have these
但当你开始构建一个巨大的应用并拥有这些
reuseable components and really strong public APIs that
可重复使用的组件和真正强大的公共api
you're willing to support, and things like that, then you'll
你愿意支持，这样的事情，你就会
find that your application is gonna have less bugs,
发现你的应用程序会有更少的bug，
and it's gonna be able to grow over time.
随着时间的推移，它也会成长。
And you're gonna be able to work in teams better, so
你可以在团队中工作得更好，所以
it's just good all around.
到处都很好。
In my viewDidLoad, I put that little imageURL equals
在我的viewDidLoad中，我把这个小imageURL等于
DemoURL.stanford that was just for testing.
DemoURL。只是为了测试。
Now that we know that it works,
现在我们知道它起作用了，
I'm just gonna delete that so
我要把它删掉
that my ImageViewController again can be reusable.
我的ImageViewController可以是可重用的。
This is its public API, which happens to be its model.
这是它的公共API，恰好是它的模型。
It's not that unusual,
这并不是说不寻常,
by the way, for the public API of a view controller
顺便说一下，对于视图控制器的公共API
to be to set the model, that's quite actually common.
要建立模型，这很常见。
So that's our model, it's the URL for
这是我们的模型，它是URL
the image you wanna show, and it's public.
你想要展示的形象，以及它的公众形象。
So we're gonna be using that when we build the rest of
我们在构建剩下的部分时会用到它
So our storyboard so far just has this one image view
到目前为止，我们的故事板只有一个图像视图
our app.
我们的应用程序。
controller right here, and I'm just gonna rapidly go through
控制器在这里，我要快速浏览一下
and build a multiple MVC app.
并构建一个多MVC应用程序。
What we're gonna do is just use our generic image
我们要做的就是使用我们的通用图像
controller MVC here to view images related to
控制器MVC用于查看与之相关的图像
the Cassini project,
卡西尼号的项目,
which is a space probe that was sent out to Saturn.
这是一个发射到土星的太空探测器。
To do that, it's gonna be all the things you know.
要做到这一点，它将是你所知道的一切。
I'm going to get it build another MVC, so
我要让它建立另一个MVC
here let's drag out another MVC.
这里我们拖出另一个MVC。
Let's create a class for it.
让我们为它创建一个类。
It's a Cocoa Touch Class, of course,
这是一个Cocoa Touch类，当然，
I'm gonna call it Cassini, my CassiniViewController.
我把它叫做Cassini，我的CassiniViewController。
I'm gonna put it in the same place that I put all my other
我要把它放在我把其他东西放进去的地方
files here, and here's my CassiniViewController.
文件在这里，这是我的CassiniViewController。
I'm gonna remove my ViewController lifecycle but
我要删除我的ViewController生命周期
I'm gonna leave my prepare for segue, without the comments,
我要准备segue，没有注释，
because I am going to be segueing from this
因为我要从这里segue
CassiniViewController to my ImageViewController.
CassiniViewController ImageViewController。
So the way this UI is gonna work is I'm just gonna have
UI的工作方式就是
three buttons here in Cassini,
卡西尼号有三个按钮，
similar to how we had with the emotions application.
类似于我们的情绪应用。
And these three buttons are going to pick these three URLs
这三个按钮将会选择这三个url
right here that are from NASA here, jpl.nasa.gov.
这里是NASA的jpl.nasa.gov。
One's of Cassini itself, one's of the Earth and
一个是卡西尼，一个是地球
one is of Saturn, so we're just gonna have three buttons
一个是土星，所以我们只有三个按钮
that let you pick those three images.
让你选择这三个图像。
So let's build that UI.
我们来构建这个UI。
First of all, let's make sure we set our identity.
首先，让我们确定我们的身份。
We just dragged out a generic ViewController,
我们只是拖出一个通用的视图控制器，
we obviously want its identity to be a specific subclass,
显然，我们希望它的身份是一个特定的子类，
in this case, the CassiniViewController,
在这个例子中，CassiniViewController，
just like this one is an ImageViewController.
就像这个是ImageViewController。
So let's drag this out to make the button a little bigger,
把这个拖出来，让按钮变大一点，
to get a bigger font.
得到更大的字体。
Try a maybe 40 point, something like that.
试试大概40点，像这样。
The three buttons that I had, one was Earth, I'll just do
我有三个按钮，一个是地球，我就这么做
copy and paste, make a couple more buttons here, another one
复制粘贴，在这里多做几个按钮，另一个
was Cassini itself, another one was Saturn.
卡西尼号本身，另一个是土星。
And we'll just select these and we'll put them in a stack
我们选择这些，然后把它们放到堆栈中
view, and we'll put some spacing between, and
视图，我们会把间隔设为
we'll fill, and fill equally.
我们将填满，并同样填满。
We'll take it and drag it to the middle here.
我们把它拖到中间。
We'll use our blue lines to put it in the middle, so
我们用蓝色的线把它放到中间
that we can go down here, and
我们可以往下走
say Reset to Suggested Constraints.
重置为建议的约束。
We can go to our Size Inspector here just to verify
我们可以去找我们的尺寸检验员来验证一下
that the constraints it added seem like the ones we want,
它添加的约束似乎是我们想要的，
which definitely does seem like that.
这显然是这样的。
Let's go ahead and,
让我们继续,
one thing I wanna show you a little different this
我想向你们展示一个不同的东西
time is before we started with a SplitViewController and
时间是在我们使用SplitViewController开始之前
then I added the navigation controller in.
然后我添加了导航控制器。
In other words, I started with an iPad UI,
换句话说，我从一个iPad UI开始，
building an iPad UI, and then I made it also work on iPhone.
建立一个iPad用户界面，然后我也在iPhone上做了它。
We can do the other way around as well.
我们也可以这样做。
So we could take this view controller, which is the one,
我们可以用这个视图控制器，
the base one that we want to show, and
这是我们想要展示的基础
we can say embed it in a Navigation Controller.
我们可以把它嵌入到导航控制器中。
And then, obviously, we want to make this
显然，我们要做这个
navigation controller be the entry point of our app.
导航控制器是app的入口点。
I don't want to forget that, so I'm just gonna throw that
我不想忘记这个，所以我要把它扔了
little arrow over here onto the left.
小箭头在左边。
And then when we do our segues here,
当我们在这里做segue的时候，
like from Earth over to here, and from Cassini.
从地球到这里，从卡西尼。
And I'm going to Show Detail because I know eventually I'm
我将展示细节，因为我知道最终我是
also going to support the iPad, instead of Show,
也支持iPad，而不是显示，
which would only really support the iPhone.
这只会真正支持iPhone。
Because Show, remember, if you do a Show and
因为Show，记住，如果你做一个节目
you're in the master of an iPad, it'll actually,
你在iPad的主人那里，实际上，
if you're in Navigation Controller in the master of
如果你在导航控制器中
the iPad and you do Show, it's going to replace the mster,
iPad会显示，它将取代mster，
whereas Show Detail replaces the detail.
而显示细节则取代了细节。
So here I have these three segues.
这里有三个segue。
I'm gonna kinda cheat a little bit and
我有点作弊了
have my segue identifiers just be the names of these
我的segue标识符是这些的名称吗
URLs right here, so Cassini, Earth, and Saturn,
这里的url，卡西尼，地球和土星，
that's gonna be my segue identifiers.
这是我的segue标识符。
I say it's cheating because normally your identifier would
我说这是作弊，因为通常你的标识符会
just identify the segue, and
只要识别segue，然后
then you would get the information somewhere else,
然后你会得到其他地方的信息，
but just to make our code really, really simple.
只是为了让我们的代码非常简单。
Oops, that's not Earth, that one's Saturn.
哦，那不是地球，那是土星。
And then let's go to this one, wait, where's our Earth?
然后再看这个，等等，地球在哪里?
And we go to this one, oops, this one rather,
我们看这个，哦，这个，
that is Cassini.
这是卡西尼。
Okay, so we built our UI here.
我们在这里建立了UI。
Now, this would be really only an iPhone appropriate UI.
现在，这只是一个iPhone合适的UI。
If we run this on iPhone, it actually would look fine,
如果我们在iPhone上运行这个，它看起来会很好，
you'll see.
你会看到。
Now why doesn't this work as is?
为什么不像现在这样?
You see I had this right here, and I get this modal view,
你看到我在这里有这个，然后我得到这个模态视图，
it kinda came up.
它有点上来。
Obviously, we have no image selected yet,
很明显，我们还没有选定图像，
we haven't written any prepare code.
我们还没有编写任何代码。
But there's no back here.
但这里没有。
Why is there no back?
为什么没有回来?
That's because of this things being show detail.
这是因为这些东西都很详细。
Because show detail only works in the iPad configuration.
因为show detail只在iPad配置中工作。
So like, if I change this to being a show.
所以，如果我把它改成一个show。
Well, actually, I'm not sure, someone was
事实上，我不确定，有人
saying that to we have to remake that one to be a show.
说到我们必须重拍那个节目。
Let's see if that works.
让我们看看它是否有效。
And this is where it goes Saturn.
这就是土星所在的地方。
Cuz we're not being prepared.
因为我们没有准备好。
All right, see?
好了,看到了吗?
So now it pushes, we're inside the navigation controller.
现在它在推，我们在导航控制器里。
We can go back.
我们可以回去。
But this is an iPhone only and we don't want that.
但这只是一部iPhone，我们不想要它。
We want to work on both platforms.
我们想在这两个平台上工作。
So I am gonna take that out again,
所以我要把它取出来，
and put this back to be showed detail.
然后把它放回细节。
Anyway, so I have this nice iPhone API, or UI rather.
不管怎样，我有一个很好的iPhone API，或者说UI。
And I wanna turn into split view if, so
我想把它变成分屏视图
I am going the other way and terms of preparing it.
我要用另一种方式来准备它。
So lets go down here and grab a split view.
让我们从这里开始，抓取一个分屏视图。
I drag it out here,
我把它拖出来，
remember it brings all this other junk with it.
记住，它带来了所有其他的垃圾。
We close our document outline,
我们关闭了文件大纲，
you can delete these things that came with it.
你可以删除这些附带的东西。
Now we have our Split View Controller right here, and
现在我们有了分屏视图控制器
we can just use Ctrl+Drag to make this be our master.
我们可以用Ctrl +拖动来让它成为我们的master。
And we can put this down here, let's say,
我们可以把它写在这里，
in control drag to make this be our detail.
在control拖动中，这是我们的细节。
And let's make our entry point the display view and
让我们进入显示视图
just like that now,
就像现在一样,
we turn this into something that can work on iPad.
我们把它变成可以在iPad上运行的东西。
But having these segues we show versus show detail is
但我们展示的这些segue与显示的细节是不同的
kind of an annoying little difference between the two
这两者之间有点不一样
platforms.
平台。
So you kinda have to know whether you're gonna put
所以你必须知道你是否会
it into split view or not unfortunately,
很不幸，
when you build your app.
当你建立你的应用程序。
Now, this will still work on iPhone.
现在，这仍然适用于iPhone。
Just begins on the detail to start and
就从开始的细节开始
we can navigate here into these various things.
我们可以在这里浏览各种各样的东西。
And it will also work on iPad,
它也适用于iPad，
lets see iPad.
让我们看看iPad。
Here is the thing we can slide out our master,
这是我们可以从我们的主人那里滑出的东西，
I click on these things or we can go to landscape.
我点击这些东西，或者我们可以去风景。
And again, it's not showing anything cuz I haven't yet.
再一次，它没有显示任何我还没有的东西。
on iPad maybe we want to put this in a navigation
在iPad上，我们想把它放在导航栏里
Now, again,
现在,再一次,
controller right here so, we get a nice title over here.
控制器在这里，这里有一个很好的标题。
So I can do that as well, just go down here and
我也可以这样做，在下面这里
select this new controller down here and
在这里选择这个新控制器
do embed in navigation control.
在导航控制中嵌入。
Now if we do that,
如果我们这样做，
we're gonna be want to be careful in our prepare.
我们在准备时要小心。
That when we prepare for this segue, we account for
当我们为这个segue做准备时，我们需要考虑
this navigation controller perhaps being there.
这个导航控制器可能在那里。
And I'm gonna show you how to do that as well.
我也会告诉你们怎么做。
Let's do our prepare.
让我们做准备。
We've got our UI,
我们有我们的UI,
same kinda UI as we did in emotions, exactly the same.
就像我们在情感中所做的那样，完全一样。
But obviously nothing works in these segues unless we
但很明显，这些segue里没有任何东西，除非我们
So, let's go to our prepare for segue here and type it in.
所以，让我们进入prepareforsegue，并输入它。
prepare.
准备。
It's gonna be a really simple prepare for segue,
这将是一个很简单的prepareforsegue，
cuz I made the segue identifier be the thing I'm
因为我做了segue标识符
gonna look up in the table.
在桌子上抬头看。
So I'm just gonna say if I can let the URL,
我想说，如果我可以让URL，
that I want the NASA URL, equal DemoURL.NASA.
我想要NASA的网址，equal demourl . NASA。
And I'm gonna look it up, by taking the segue identifier,
我将通过segue标识符来查找它，
but if that segue identified with nil, this won't work.
但如果这个segue被nil识别，这就行不通了。
In other words,
换句话说,
you can't look up something that's an optional,
你不能找一个可选的，
like the identifier is, in a dictionary.
像标识符一样，在字典里。
This dictionary is looking for a string here.
这本字典在找一个字符串。
So, I'm just gonna say defaulting to nothing.
那么，我就说默认为零。
And of course, looking this up in this dictionary,
当然，在这本字典里，
it's gonna return nil.
它会返回nil。
But I'm doing if let right here, so that's okay.
但如果我在这里做，就可以了。
Now I'm getting the URL if possible, so that segue,
现在我得到了URL，如果可能的话，那么这个segue，
if it's possible to get that URL out of
如果有可能的话
the NASA dictionary, then I will do that.
NASA的字典，我就这么做。
Now, of course,
现在,当然,
I need the view controller that I'm segueing to.
我需要segue到的视图控制器。
So I'm gonna say,
所以我想说,
if I can let imageVC = (segue.destination as?
如果我可以让imageVC =(segue)目的地是?
ImageViewController.
ImageViewController。
That's that view controller that we're segueing to.
这就是我们segue到的视图控制器。
If I can do that, then I can prepare.
如果我能做到，我就能做好准备。
But of course, here we've got the problem where this
当然，这里有一个问题
destination on an iPad might be, what?
在iPad上的目的地可能是什么?
A navigation controller.
一个导航控制器。
So normally, we would put a little if in here,
通常情况下，如果在这里，
we say if the thing is a navigation controller,
我们说如果它是一个导航控制器，
then we would get the visible view controller.
然后我们会得到可见的视图控制器。
Remember that code that we put in there?
还记得我们输入的代码吗?
You probably put that in your homework,
你们可能把它放在作业里，
if you used navigation control for your detail.
如果你使用导航控制你的细节。
Instead, I'm gonna put that in an extension,
相反，我将把它放到一个扩展中，
remember we learned about extensions last time?
还记得上次我们学过的扩展吗?
So I'm going to extend UI view controller, and
我将扩展uiviewcontroller
just add a var to UIViewController.
只需添加一个var到UIViewController。
Now this var I'm gonna add, I'm gonna call it contents,
现在我要添加这个var，我把它命名为contents，
and it's going to be of type UIViewController.
它将会是UIViewController类型。
And since it's in the extension,
因为它在扩展中，
it can't be a var that has any storage.
它不可能是一个有任何存储的var。
Extensions have no storage.
扩展没有存储。
So it can only be a computed var so I'm gonna compute it.
它只能是一个计算的var，所以我要计算它。
And what is contents gonna be, what is this var?
什么是内容，什么是var ?
Well, I'm defining contents to be the contents of this
我将内容定义为它的内容
view controller, what this view controller holds?
视图控制器，这个视图控制器是什么?
Well, if this view controller is a navigation controller,
如果这个视图控制器是一个导航控制器，
then tha's the visible view controller.
然后是可见的视图控制器。
If it's not, then it's just itself,
如果不是，那么它就是它自己，
a view controller's contents are itself.
视图控制器的内容本身就是。
Unless, it happens to be a navigation controller and
除非，它恰好是一个导航控制器
then it returns to visible view controller.
然后它返回到可见的视图控制器。
I could also,
我也可以,
And if I am, show the visible tab, too.
如果我是，也显示可见选项卡。
But for interest of time I won't do that,
但为了时间的利益，我不会那样做，
you can do that if you want.
如果你愿意，你可以这样做。
I'm just gonna say here if I can let navcon = self as?
如果我可以让navcon = self ?
a UINavigationController.
UINavigationController。
In other words, if I'm a navigation controller then I'm
换句话说，如果我是导航控制器
just going to return the navcon's visible.
只需要返回navcon的可见值。
Navcon is myself,
Navcon是我自己,
it's just that it's myself as a navigation controller.
只是我自己作为导航控制器。
So I can send this var, I can get this var from it.
所以我可以发送这个var，我可以从它得到这个var。
Of course, this visible view controller is optional
当然，这个可见的视图控制器是可选的
because the navigation controller might not have any
因为导航控制器可能没有
view controller in it at the moment.
视图控制器此时此刻。
So, I better have a default there which I'll just
因此，我最好有一个默认值
return self.
回归自我。
And then if I'm not in navigation controller,
如果我不在导航控制器中，
then I'm just gonna return self.
然后我返回self。
So you see how content, it's showing the contents of our
你可以看到内容，它显示了我们的内容
navigation folder, otherwise, it's returning myself.
导航文件夹，否则，它返回自己。
Which is kind of cool for this situation.
这对这种情况很酷。
And it allows me to go up here, instead of saying segue
它允许我向上走，而不是说segue
destination, I can just say sequedestination.content.
目的地,我可以说sequedestination.content。
And then I don't need this little if up there.
然后我就不需要这个了。
Now, is this a reasonable thing to do in extension?
这是一个合理的扩展吗?
Absolutely it is, because this var has complete and
当然，因为这个var已经完整了
utter understandable semantics that only have to do
完全可以理解的语义，只需要做
with the UI view controller and
使用UI视图控制器
nothing to do with Casini view controller or anything else.
与Casini视图控制器或其他东西无关。
Because when you do an extension,
因为当你做一个扩展时，
you want that to be the case.
你想要这样。
You don't wanna generally put extensions on other classes
一般不需要在其他类上添加扩展名
that have to do with other classes, generally.
一般来说，这与其他类有关。
Unless they're kind of like standard types, or
除非它们有点像标准类型
something like that.
就像这样。
Maybe converting from a string to a date,
也许从一个字符串转换到一个日期，
or something like that.
之类的。
In some way might make some sense, but
从某种意义上说，可能有些道理
you wouldn't want to put extensions on other classes
您不想在其他类上添加扩展
that are specific to things that other classes need.
这是特定于其他类需要的东西。
In that case, just put a function in your own class
在这种情况下，只需在自己的类中添加一个函数
that does that thing.
那件事。
So does everyone see what I'm saying about this?
大家都明白我的意思了吗?
This makes perfect sense,
这非常有意义,
this would be usable in any environment,
这在任何环境下都是可用的，
it's a sensible var to have on a view controller.
在视图控制器上有一个合理的var。
Now that I have my image view controller,
现在我有了图像视图控制器，
either by getting it or
要么得到它，要么
going through the navigation controller, I can prepare it.
通过导航控制器，我可以准备它。
And so preparing it is really easy,
所以准备很简单，
I just wanna set the URL equal to that URL, okay,
我只想设置URL等于这个URL，
the URL that I got out of the demo URL.
我从演示URL中得到的URL。
This is just public API, okay, this happens to be its model,
这是公共API，这恰好是它的模型，
let's also set its title.
让我们也设置它的标题。
We can set the title equal to,
我们可以把标题设为，
we could do the same thing we did before.
我们可以像以前一样做。
Take the sender interpret it as a UI button and
以发送者将其解释为UI按钮
if we're able to do that then we'll get the current title.
如果我们能这样做，我们就会得到当前的标题。
Which might be nil, but
可能是nil，但是
that's okay because this is also an optional.
这没问题，因为这也是一个可选的。
This is optional so can take a nil even though this is nil.
这是可选的，所以可以取nil，尽管这是nil。
And of course it might be nil because this turns out to not
当然它可能是nil，因为结果不是
be true, and that's fine, too.
是真的，那也很好。
See how these optionals play out nicely because you have
看看这些选项是如何发挥作用的，因为你有
vars that are optional and things are optional?
可选的vars是可选的?
So you can set things equal to each other and
所以你可以把它们设成相等的
it kind of just all plays out kind of beautifully there.
它在那里的效果都很好。
So that's it, let's run here.
就是这样，我们在这里运行。
Let's see
让我们看看
what we got.
我们得到了什么。
Here we go. So
我们开始吧。所以
let's take a look at Cassini, for
让我们来看看卡西尼号
example, look, it's broken.
看,它坏了。
Whoa, what's going on?
哇,这是怎么回事?
I clicked there to get Cassini which, look, there's Cassini.
我点了一下卡西尼，看，卡西尼号。
Let's zoom in on Cassini.
让我们放大卡西尼号。
There it is.
在这里。
So this is the Cassini space probe right here by Saturn.
这是土星的卡西尼号太空探测器。
But when I clicked on it, it seemed like my UI froze.
但当我点击它的时候，我的UI就被冻结了。
And if I click on these other ones, look,
如果我点击其他的，
I'm clicking Saturn, Saturn, Saturn, nothing's happening.
我点击土星，土星，土星，什么都没发生。
Because it, now something came up.
因为它，现在出现了一些东西。
So this UI seems broken.
这个UI看起来是坏的。
Now we're on ultra fast network here.
现在我们在超快的网络上。
This is Stanford's network.
这是斯坦福大学的网络。
We have like gigabyte connections to everywhere and
我们有十亿字节的连接到任何地方和
it still took a while cuz it's a very large file.
它仍然需要一段时间，因为它是一个非常大的文件。
Imagine I was on cellular.
想象一下，我在手机上。
That image might take a minute to download.
这个图像可能需要一分钟才能下载。
And meanwhile my app is completely stuck,
与此同时，我的应用完全卡住了，
I can't click on any other button.
我不能点击任何其他的按钮。
If I'm on iPhone,
如果我在iPhone上,
lets see what he looks like on iPhone, it's even worse.
让我们看看他在iPhone上的样子，情况更糟。
If I'm on iPhone, I'm gonna click that.
如果我在iPhone上，我会点击它。
I'm gonna think, " my app is broken".
我想，"我的app坏了"
So I'm in a NavigationController,
我在导航控制器中，
no problem, I'll just hit back.
没问题，我打回去。
But even the back button's
但即使是back按钮
not gonna work, as you'll see.
不去工作，你会看到的。
All right, so here we are.
好的，我们到了。
Got the detailed view there.
这里有详细的视图。
Now I'm gonna hit Earth, it's stuck.
现在我要撞上地球了，它卡住了。
And again, I can't do anything.
再说一次，我什么都做不了。
Finally comes back.
终于回来了。
So this kinda UI is horrible because, especially on
这个UI很可怕，尤其是
cellular or something where it's really slow,
细胞或者其他一些非常缓慢的地方，
users are like, this app is broken.
用户就像，这个app坏了。
They're literally going to double-click the Home
他们会双击房子
button and flip your app off, to use an analogy there.
按下你的应用程序，用一个类比。
They're gonna flip your app and kill it because their,
他们会翻转你的应用，然后杀了它，
they think it's broken.
他们认为这是坏了。
So we're gonna fix that with multitasking.
我们要用多任务处理来解决这个问题。
So first, let me show
首先，我来展示一下
you how that works.
你是怎么做的。
All right, so, multithreading.
好吧,所以,多线程。
There's two reasons generally,
通常有两个原因,
that you wanna do multithreading.
你想要多线程。
One reason is, you have a mathematical problem, or
一个原因是，你有一个数学问题，或者
some image processing problem, that is best solved
一些图像处理问题，这是最好的解决方法
using some kind of parallel processing algorithm where you
使用一种并行处理算法
wanna go off and do 1000 things or 100 things at once.
想要一次性完成1000件或100件事情。
And then and when they're all done together you're gonna
然后，当他们一起完成的时候，你就会
combine the result, or something like that.
结合结果，或者类似的东西。
So that's an obvious need to do multithreading.
这显然需要多线程处理。
That's not the multithreading I'm gonna be
那不是我要做的多线程
talking to you about.
和你谈话。
That, that's a perfectly valid use of multithreading,
这是多线程的有效使用，
iOS has some great API for doing that kind of design.
iOS有一些很棒的API来做这种设计。
But that's not what I'm talking about.
但这不是我要说的。
The second reason that you might wanna do multithreading
第二个原因可能是多线程
is because you have one thread.
因为你有一个线程。
By the way, does everyone know what a thread is?
顺便问一下，大家都知道线程是什么吗?
Raise your hand if you know what a thread is.
如果你知道线是什么，请举手。
Okay, I see some people saying, yeah, remind me.
好吧，我看到有人说，是的，提醒我。
A thread just means, thread is short for thread of execution.
线程只是意味着，线程是执行线程的缩写。
And it just is kind of a, the process,
这是一个过程，
through which code is executing.
通过该代码执行。
That could conceivably be separated where you have
这可能会被分开
multiple of them.
的倍数。
in the iOS, you've got a very important kind of main thread
在iOS中，你有一个非常重要的主线程
For example,
例如,
That's the thread of execution that is listening to gestures
这是执行的主线，倾听手势
of execution.
的执行。
and doing drawing, things like that.
画图画之类的。
Then you can have other threads of execution that
然后你可以有其他的执行线程
might be doing background things, like going out onto
可能做一些背景的事情，比如出去
the network and getting data, or something like that.
网络和获取数据，或者类似的东西。
Most of our devices aren't multiprocessor, per se, so
我们的大多数设备都不是多处理器，所以
these threads, although they have multiple cores, so
这些线程，虽然它们有多个内核，所以
they can actually do two things at once.
他们实际上可以同时做两件事。
They literally can.
他们真的可以。
But in this case where I'm talking about multithreading
但在这种情况下，我说的是多线程
to solve this problem of keeping the UI responsive,
为了解决保持UI响应的问题，
we don't even care about that.
我们甚至不关心这个。
And so here's the thing with multithreading and the UI.
这里是多线程和UI。
We want the thread of execution which is listening
我们想要执行的线程正在监听
to the user to be super responsive, always working,
要让用户反应灵敏，一直工作，
never blocked.
不会阻塞。
And we don't really care about other threads too much,
我们并不太关心其他的线程，
but we really want that one to be unblocked at all time.
但我们真的希望它能一直畅通无阻。
So if we're ever going to do anything that would block,
所以如果我们要做任何会阻碍的事情，
like either block because it's doing so much computation
就像任何一个block一样，因为它做了很多计算
that it's not getting back to the rest of the code.
它不会回到代码的其余部分。
Or in this case, with our Cassini, it's gonna block
或者在这种情况下，用卡西尼号，它会阻塞
because it's waiting on some resource like the network.
因为它在等一些资源，比如网络。
Okay, I make a request for a URL.
我请求URL。
It doesn't respond immediately, I have to wait.
它没有立即响应，我必须等待。
Any time I have to wait, I can't be waiting in the middle
任何时候我都得等，我不能在中间等
of that UI cuz now no one can do a gesture or
在这个UI中，现在没有人可以做手势
click on the back button or do anything else.
单击后退按钮或做其他事情。
So that's the kind of multithreading that I'm
这就是我说的多线程
talking about here that we're gonna try and
说到这里，我们会尝试
solve, is keep the UI thread responsive and active
解决，就是保持UI线程的响应性和活动性
by pushing everything else that could be slow or blocked,
把其他的东西都推得很慢或堵塞，
waiting on a resource, off to a different thread.
在资源上等待，在不同的线程上等待。
Now in iOS,
现在在iOS,
we don't actually even really talk about threads much.
我们实际上并没有过多地讨论线程。
I've been using this word thread,
我一直在用这个词，
because that's what's going on underneath the covers.
因为这就是封面下面的内容。
We're talking about threads of execution here.
我们说的是执行的线程。
But really, what we talk about is queues.
但实际上，我们谈论的是队列。
So multithreading is really about queues.
多线程实际上是关于队列的。
Now what's a queue?
现在一个队列是什么?
Queue is an English word, actually.
实际上，队列是一个英语单词。
We don't use it in the United States much, but
我们在美国不用它，但是
a queue just means a line.
队列就是一条直线。
Like if you go to the movies, you might say, I'm queueing up
如果你去看电影，你可能会说，我在排队
to see this movie, especially if you were in London,
为了看这部电影，特别是如果你在伦敦，
you would say let's go queue for the movie.
你会说让我们去排队看电影吧。
So that's all a queue is, it's a line.
这就是队列，这是一条直线。
And what are we gonna put in this line?
我们在这条直线上写什么呢?
Instead of people waiting for
而不是等待
the movie, we're gonna put blocks of code.
电影，我们要把代码块放进去。
And we know a great way to make a block of code that we
我们知道一个很好的方法来做一个代码块
can put in a line which is a closure.
可以输入一条闭合的线。
So we're almost always doing this with closure.
所以我们几乎总是用闭包来做。
So putting these closures, it could be any blocking code,
把这些闭包，可以是任何阻塞代码，
but we're putting these closures basically,
但是我们把这些闭包，
usually into a queue.
通常在一个队列。
And so what's happening then is the system
那么系统就是这样的
is creating threads as necessary to grab those
创建线程是为了获取这些吗
blocks off that queue, off the front of the line, who's ever
挡在队伍前面，排在队伍前面，谁是谁
in the front of the queue and executing on a thread.
在队列的前面，在线程上执行。
That's how multitasking or
这就是多任务或
multithreading really works in iOS.
多线程确实在iOS中有效。
We don't really care how the system assigns threads to
我们并不关心系统如何分配线程
these lines, these queues.
这些线,这些队列。
All we care about is the queues.
我们只关心队列。
And when we wanna express to the system where we want
当我们想要表达我们想要的系统的时候
things to run, you know, where the UI runs or
运行的东西，UI运行的地方
in background process or whatever,
在后台进程中，
we specify it by what queue we put code on.
我们通过使用代码来指定它。
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗?
Let's talk about the queues that we can have.
我们来讨论一下我们可以使用的队列。
One important queue, of course, is the main queue.
当然，一个重要的队列是主队列。
So this is the queue on which all the UI
这是所有UI的队列
activity is happening.
活动正在发生的事情。
It's not only the queue that all UI activity is happening
它不仅仅是所有UI活动都在发生的队列
But it's the only queue that UI activity can happen on.
但它是UI活动能够发生的唯一队列。
in general.
一般来说。
And that's because it's a serial queue.
这是因为它是一个串行队列。
A serial queue is a queue where everyone,
串行队列是每个人的队列，
the blocks in code are waiting in line to run,
代码中的代码块正在排队等待运行，
and there's only one thread to run them.
只有一个线程来运行它们。
So when the system comes along to grab the next guy in line,
所以当系统来抓下一个人的时候，
he runs him to completion and then goes back for
他让他完成任务，然后回去
the next one.
下一个。
So you see how they're serial.
看它们是如何串联的。
They happen in order.
他们发生在订单。
The entire line of closures waiting to run, or code
所有闭包等待运行，或代码
waiting to run, is processed in order, one at a time.
等待运行，按顺序处理，一次一个。
What's really great about the UI side of that is it
UI方面真正伟大的是它
makes it very predictable.
很可预测的。
You really don't have to get into a lot of the mind games
你真的不必去玩心理游戏了
of multithreading, where it's like, is this thing waiting on
在多线程的情况下，这是一个等待的东西
this, do I have to have a lock on this data resource bug?
这个，我必须要锁定这个数据资源bug吗?
Because all the UI stuff is all happening in
因为所有的UI都发生了
the main queue.
主要的队列。
This is all happening serially,
这都是连续发生的，
you never have to worry about two UI things accessing
您永远不必担心访问的两个UI
the same data structure at the same time,
相同的数据结构，
cuz they're all just marching in line, down this main queue.
因为它们都排成一行，沿着主队排。
So, all UI activity and only UI activity, no other stuff,
所有UI活动和UI活动，没有其他东西，
generally, runs in the UI, the main queue.
通常，在UI中运行主队列。
And the reason we don't want other stuff running in the
我们不希望其他东西在这里运行的原因
main queue, is we never want the main queue to be blocked.
主队列，我们不希望主队列被阻塞。
We never want it to be off doing some computation or,
我们不希望它停止计算或者，
certainly, never blocked waiting for
当然，永远不要阻止等待
the network or something.
网络什么的。
So that's the main queue,
这是主队列，
that's the most important queue, and then,
这是最重要的队列，然后，
there are these other queues.
还有其他的队列。
I'm gonna talk first about the global queues.
我首先要讲的是全局队列。
The global queues are different kind of queues.
全局队列是不同类型的队列。
These global queues, people wait in line to go onto those,
这些全球队列，人们排队等着去看这些，
and at the other end of the line the system has multiple
在线的另一端，系统有多个
threads ready to go.
线程准备好了。
And it can pull a closure off the line, give it a thread,
它可以拉出一条线，给它一条线，
it starts running, pulls another one off,
它开始运行，又拉掉一个，
it starts running before the first one's even done.
它在第一个人完成之前就开始运行了。
So those are called concurrent queues.
这些被称为并发队列。
The queues where you could be pulling people off the line
你可以把人们从队伍中拉出来的队伍
cuz you got multiple threads to assign to the task.
因为你有多个线程来分配任务。
So, things we do outside the UI,
我们在UI之外做的事情，
like network things and things that block, we're generally
就像网络事物和事物一样，我们通常
gonna do those in these global concurrent queues.
在全局并发队列中执行这些操作。
You can also create your own serial queues and
您还可以创建自己的串行队列
your own concurrent queues.
自己的并发队列。
We'll talk about that in a couple slides.
我们将在几张幻灯片中讨论这个。
You're not going to need to do that in this class.
在这门课上你不需要这么做。
90% of the time you're either using the main queue, or
you're using one of these global concurrent queues.
您正在使用其中一个全局并发队列。
So let's talk about the code, how do you get a queue?
我们来讨论一下代码，如何得到一个队列?
I need a queue because I wanna put a block of code on this
我需要一个队列，因为我想在这个上面放一个代码块
queue, I want it to get in line to go run.
排队，我想让它排队去跑。
Well, the main queue,
主队列,
you just use this bar DispatchQueue.main.
你只需要使用这个条形DispatchQueue.main。
It's a static bar, a class bar,
这是一个静态的酒吧，一个班级酒吧，
on the class dispatch queue, and that's it,
在类调度队列中，
you have your main queue, it couldn't be easier.
你有你的主队，这是不容易的。
Now, getting one of these global concurrent queues,
现在，获取一个全局并发队列，
a little bit more work.
还有一点功。
You're going to use DispatchQueue.global instead
你将使用DispatchQueue。全球而不是
of DispatchQueue.main, and it takes an argument there, QoS.
DispatchQueue。主要的，它需要一个参数，QoS。
QoS stands for Quality of Service.
QoS代表服务质量。
So this is talking about how, what
这就是我们要讨论的
the quality of the service that the line is getting.
这条线所得到的服务质量。
So, high quality service means things are being pulled off
因此，高质量的服务意味着事情正在被取消
the line really fast and the threads that are being used to
这条线非常快，而且正在被使用的线程
execute them are high priority threads that get to run a lot.
执行它们是获得大量运行的高优先级线程。
Cuz remember there's only one processor, so
因为只有一个处理器，所以
they often kinda share the processor.
他们经常分享处理器。
So, high quality service means you get a lot.
因此，高质量的服务意味着你得到了很多。
Low quality services, well, the system will pull your
低质量的服务，嗯，系统会拉动你
thing off when it feels like it, like maybe the phone is,
当它感觉像手机的时候，
is well, got woken up for some other reason,
好吧，因为其他原因被唤醒，
it's not gonna wake your phone up to do it.
它不会把你的手机叫醒去做。
And it's certainly not going to block any high priority
它当然不会阻止任何高优先级
thing, that kind of thing.
就是这样。
So, but the quality of service is not like a number, 0,
但是服务的质量不像数字0，
low quality, 10, high quality, instead,
低质量，10，高质量，
it's kind of a flavor of usage.
这是一种用法的味道。
These are the four qualities of services here.
这里有四种服务品质。
So user interactive is, means the user is interacting with
用户交互是指用户交互
the UI right now, usually with a gesture.
UI现在，通常是一个手势。
They are panning around, or pinching, and your forking off
他们正在四处淘金，或者捏着，你的分叉
something into a thread to go do something.
某物进入某一线程去做某事。
Now, this is usually not a case of the thing you're gonna
这通常不是你要做的事
be doing is so intensive that it would block the main
要做的是如此的密集以至于它会阻止主要的
thread, because the person is panning right now.
线程，因为这个人现在正在平移。
But it might be something that can't quite keep up
但它可能是一些无法跟上的东西
with the finger, and you're going to deal with that by,
用手指，你要处理这个，
in this other thread, trying to keep up as best you can and
在另一个线程中，尽量保持最佳状态
just updating the main thread as fast as you can,
只要尽快更新主线程，
which might be a little slower than the fingers going.
这可能比手指要慢一点。
So, you know, the finger dragging around,
所以，你知道，手指在拖动，
maybe it's jumping a little bit because it can't calculate
也许它跳得有点高，因为它无法计算
its new position fast enough.
它的新位置足够快。
But the point is, this queue really needs to run,
但关键是，这个队列确实需要运行，
almost as bad, it's almost as high priority as the main
几乎同样糟糕的是，它几乎是主要的优先级
queue because you're doing something interactive.
排队，因为你在做一些互动的事情。
Okay, the next one is user initiated.
下一个是用户发起的。
What this means is this, the user currently did something
这意味着什么，用户现在做了什么
to initiate this activity, this can be done in
要发起这个活动，就可以这样做
this queue, so it's pretty high priority.
这个队列非常重要。
Okay, the user did something and they're waiting for
用户做了一些事情，他们在等待
a response presumably.
大概的回应。
So that would be the category for our Cassini project.
这就是卡西尼项目的分类。
We clicked Earth, or Saturn, we want that image now, and
我们点击地球，或者土星，我们现在想要那个图像
we're waiting for it.
我们等待它。
So we are gonna use, user initiated.
所以我们要使用，用户发起。
Cuz the user initiated a request for it.
因为用户提出了一个请求。
But it's gonna take a while,
但这需要一段时间，
and the user's not interacting, we're not
而用户不交互，我们不是
making it doing something different every time it moves.
让它每次移动都做些不同的事情。
We were just, it's, but it was user initiated, so
我们只是，它是用户发起的，所以
user initiated is pretty high priority.
用户发起是相当高的优先级。
Then there's background and utility.
然后是背景和效用。
These are somewhat similar.
这些都是有些相似的。
Utility is truly the deepest of background processes.
实用程序确实是最深入的后台进程。
This might be something you run once a week in your app.
这可能是你在应用程序中每周运行一次的东西。
Maybe it cleans up the database by removing old
也许它通过删除旧的来清理数据库
crufty stuff,
crufty东西,
something the user doesn't even know is going on.
一些用户甚至不知道的事情正在发生。
It's so low priority,
低优先级,
it just kind of happens in the background.
只是在背景中发生。
Background might be something that you, you,
背景可能是你，你，
like maybe you're thinking ahead a little bit about
比如你在思考
the way the user might want to use your app.
用户想要使用你的应用程序的方式。
And so you fork something off in the background to go
所以你可以在后台取一些东西
fetch some stuff or whatever.
去拿些东西什么的。
The user didn't ask you to do it, but you kind of do it.
用户并没有要求你做，但你做了。
And you kind of want it nowish but
你想要的不是它，而是
it's okay if it takes a little while.
如果需要一点时间，就可以了。
So you see what that one is.
你看这个是什么。
So these are the four qualities of service and
这就是服务的四个特点
you just need to pick which quality of service you want
你只需要选择你想要的服务质量
for your global queue.
为你的全球队列。
And then remember that the things you put on there
然后记住你在那里放的东西
are going to be run concurrently, so
会同时运行吗
they can really depend on each other.
他们真的可以互相依赖。
I'll talk about things depending on each other in
我要讲的是相互依存的关系
But this, you wanna think about the things you put on
但这个，你想想你穿的东西
a second.
第二个。
these global queues as being these
这些全球的队列就是这些
independent little things, like go fetch this file,
独立的小东西，比如去取这个文件，
it's all self contained, just give me this file.
都是自我控制的，给我这个文件。
Not blocks that are gonna be somehow depending on
不是块，这要取决于
each other's results because this is all concurrent,
彼此的结果，因为这都是并行的，
these things can be happening at exactly the same time, so
这些事情可以同时发生，所以
they can't really, it's not serial like the main queue.
他们不能真的，它不是串行的，就像主队列。
Now, like I said, you've got this queue,
现在，就像我说的，你有这个队列，
and all we're gonna do is put blocks on it and
我们要做的就是在上面加上块
we do that with these two functions, async and sync.
我们通过这两个函数来实现，异步和同步。
These two functions take one argument, which is a closure,
这两个函数有一个参数，即闭包，
a function but usually it's a closure, that closure
一个函数，但通常是闭包，闭包
function takes no arguments and returns no arguments.
函数不接受参数，不返回参数。
And you can put anything you want in that closure.
你可以把任何你想要的东西放到那个闭包里。
So, async means put this closure on the queue,
因此，async意味着把这个闭包放在队列上，
put it in the line to execute, and return immediately.
将其放入行中执行，并立即返回。
So async does nothing except for
所以async除了
put that block into the queue, whatever queue you send it to.
把那个块放到队列中，不管发送到哪个队列。
Sync, same thing, puts it in the queue and
同步，同样的，放到队列中
then it says block this thread until that closure finishes
然后它说阻塞这个线程直到关闭结束
executing on whatever queue it's on.
在任何队列上执行。
Which could be a totally different queue.
这可能是一个完全不同的队列。
So basically, the sync is block me until this closure
基本上，同步会阻塞我直到关闭
finishes executing wherever you put it.
无论你把它放在哪里，都可以执行。
So, you would never do sync on the main queue,
所以，你永远不会在主队列上同步，
cuz we never want to block the main queue.
因为我们不想阻塞主队列。
So, you would never say main queue.sync anything.
所以，你永远不会说主队列。任何同步。
But you might have other queues and say,
但你可能会说，
you know, sorry, you would say main queue, you could say main
你知道，对不起，你会说主队列，你可以说main
queue.sync, but you would say it on another thread.
队列中。同步，但你会在另一个线程上说。
You fire off some of the thread,
你点燃一些线，
it's running along in the background.
它在后台运行。
It could say main queue.sync, this code.
它可以说主队列。同步,这段代码。
Now that code would be put on the main queue.
现在，代码将放在主队列上。
Sometime later, we don't know when,
有时，我们不知道什么时候，
it would run on the main queue.
它会在主队列上运行。
Once it's done, then your thread,
一旦完成，
your queue that issued this, would continue.
您的队列发布了这个，将会继续。
So sync, we would only do the sync from code that is not on
所以同步，我们只会从代码中执行同步
the main queue, cuz we never wanna block the main queue.
主队列，因为我们不想阻塞主队列。
Question.
的问题。
Yeah, so the question is, when I say sync, am I saying,
问题是，当我说同步的时候，我是说，
let this block, this closure go first or something?
让这个方块，这个闭包先还是什么?
No, okay, this has nothing to do with priority.
不，好吧，这和优先级无关。
The priority is the quality of service.
首要的是服务的质量。
I'm just saying put this queue,
我只是说这个队列，
this closure onto the end of that queue.
这个关闭到该队列的末尾。
Now, whatever queue it is,
不管它是什么队列，
we'll have some quality of service and
我们将有一些服务质量
it will eventually get to this thing.
它最终会到达这个。
In the meantime, while all that's happening,
与此同时，当所有这些发生的时候，
this queue that this code is in is waiting, it's blocked.
这个代码正在等待的队列，它被阻塞了。
It's just blocked, waiting for that closure to finish.
它只是被阻塞，等待关闭结束。
How that closure finishes depends totally on what queue
闭包如何完成取决于队列是什么
you put it on, and how much other stuff is in that queue,
你把它放上去，还有多少东西在队列里，
and whether it's a concurrent queue, all those things.
它是否是一个并发队列，所有这些东西。
But this sync just means block me until that thing's done.
但这个同步就意味着阻止我完成它。
Question.
的问题。
So the question is, does running multiple threads,
问题是，运行多个线程，
having multiple things going in multiple threads,
在多个线程中运行多个东西，
does it slow down the main queue thread,
它会减慢主线程吗?
the thread that is running the main queue?
运行主队列的线程?
And the answer is no.
答案是否定的。
It does not usually, because the main queue is getting
它通常不会，因为主要队列是获取的
a lot of high priority.
有很多高优先级。
So it's pretty much interrupting anything those
所以很容易打断
other guys are doing whenever it wants to run, okay?
其他的人在想跑的时候都在做，对吧?
So if it wants to run,
如果它想要运行，
it pretty much gets the processor.
它几乎得到了处理器。
The main queue is the highest priority thread that exist on
主队列是存在的最高优先级线程
the device.
该设备。
So it's rarely gonna be slowed down.
所以它很少会被减速。
Now, I'm not gonna talk about this, but yes,
我不打算讲这个，但是，
threads have overhead.
线程的开销。
If you created thousands of threads,
如果你创造了成千上万的线程，
that would start slowing down your computer.
这会让你的电脑慢下来。
But again, that's why we don't really talk about threads.
但是，这也是为什么我们不讨论线程的原因。
We talk about queues and
我们谈论排队和
we let the iOS manage the threads cuz it knows how to
我们让iOS管理线程，因为它知道如何操作
efficiently manage thread pools and things like that.
有效地管理线程池和类似的东西。
You can create your own queues just using
您可以使用它创建自己的队列
a normal initializer of DispatchQueue.
DispatchQueue的普通初始化器。
Instead of saying DispatchQueue.main or
而不是说DispatchQueue。主要还是
DispatchQueue.global, you say DispatchQueue
DispatchQueue。全球,你说DispatchQueue
with the initializer that takes a label that makes
带有一个标签的初始化器
a serial queue.
一个串行队列。
And that label, it shows up in the debugger.
这个标签出现在调试器中。
So in the debugger if you pause and
在调试器中，如果你暂停
that queue is running a thread,
这个队列正在运行一个线程，
you'll see that thread in the little debugger window on
您将在“小调试器”窗口中看到该线程
the left in the navigator with this name, this label,
导航器中左边的这个名称，这个标签，
so it's just purely for seeing it in the debugger.
这纯粹是在调试器中看到的。
And if you wanna make your own concurrent queue.
如果你想创建自己的并发队列。
A queue that has multiple threads that can be working
一个具有多个可工作线程的队列
on things.
上的东西。
Then same thing, except you put attributes.concurrent,
同样的，除了你把attributes. concurrent，
in the initializer there.
在初始值设定项。
You won't need to do that in this class and
在这个课程中你不需要这样做
rarely do we do this.
我们很少这样做。
It's usually main queue and
它通常是主队列
the global queues 90% of the time.
全球排在90%的时间。
All right, I'm only showing you the absolute tip
好吧，我只是给你们看绝对小费
of the iceberg for multithreading.
关于多线程的冰山。
I'm showing you the basic stuff you need to get stuff
我向你们展示了一些基本的东西
off of the main thread but there is a lot more.
除了主线程，还有很多。
You're gonna wanna familiarize yourself eventually with
你要让自己熟悉一下
DispatchQueue and all the things that it can do.
DispatchQueue和它能做的所有事情。
This stuff is all based on something
这些东西都是基于某些东西的
called Grand Central Dispatch.
称为中央调度。
Because when we put a closure onto a queue,
因为当我们把一个闭包放到一个队列上时，
we call that dispatching the closure onto that queue.
我们调用它将闭包发送到该队列。
For those of you who do know about multithreading,
对于那些了解多线程的人，
you can do all the things you can expect,
你可以做所有你能想到的事情，
protecting critical sections, readers and writers, you know,
保护重要的章节，读者和作家，你知道，
single writer multiple readers.
单个作家多个读者。
You can do synchronous dispatch, you can do locking,
可以进行同步调度，也可以锁定，
all the things you need to do you can do.
你需要做的所有事情都可以做到。
I'm not gonna talk about any of that, but it's all there.
我不打算讲这些，但都在那里。
There is another API for doing multithreading,
还有一个用于多线程的API，
OperationQueue and Operation, these are classes.
操作队列和操作，这些是类。
Classes or structs, I guess they're classes.
类或结构，我想它们是类。
And you'll see those occasionally in iOS API,
在iOS API中偶尔会看到，
kinda older iOS API.
有点旧的iOS API。
But for the program you're gonna do, again,
但是对于你要做的程序，
unless you got the kind of multithreading problem, which
除非你有多线程问题
is doing a parallel processing thing, not the kind of problem
做一个并行处理的事情，不是问题吗
where you're getting something off the main queue.
你从主队列中得到一些东西。
Operation and OperationQueue are nice because it makes easy
操作和操作队列很好，因为它很简单
to make dependencies.
依赖关系。
Where you say this block of code
你在哪里说这段代码
depends on this one running first,
取决于这个先跑，
I need the result from this one before I can do this one.
在我做这个之前，我需要这个结果。
So you can set up those relationships,
你可以建立这些关系，
then you can say, now I just start running them.
然后你可以说，现在我开始运行它们。
And the system
和系统
will make sure this one gets run before this one, etc.
确保这个在这个之前运行，等等。
All those dependencies.
所有这些依赖关系。
So that's Operation and OperationQueue.
这就是操作和操作队列。
you'll see certain methods that are multithreaded.
您将看到一些多线程的方法。
In iOS,
在iOS,
And you'll see that in the documentation,
你会在文档中看到，
you'll read in the documentation.
您将在文档中阅读。
And the way it works is you're gonna see a method that takes
它工作的方式就是你会看到一个方法
a closure as an argument, and it'll say in the documentation
一个闭包作为一个参数，它会在文档中说
this closure is run on another thread off the main queue.
这个闭包在主队列的另一个线程上运行。
And when you see that,
当你看到它的时候，
you have to go, uh-oh, because any code I put in that closure
你必须要走，因为任何代码都是关闭的
that I'm passing to this function can't be doing any
我传递给这个函数的过程是不可能的
UI stuff because that only can happen on the main queue.
UI，因为它只会发生在主队列上。
And this happens quite a lot, that we have a closure that
这种情况经常发生，我们有一个闭包
we're putting on some background queue, or
我们设置了一些后台队列
passing to some iOS function,
传递到一些iOS函数，
that says it's not gonna put it on the main queue.
也就是说，它不会把它放到主队列上。
But we still wanna do UI stuff, so how do we do that?
但我们还是想做UI，怎么做呢?
We just dispatch it back to the main queue.
我们只需将它发送回主队列。
And this is what that looks like.
这就是它的样子。
Here is an iOS API that takes a closure as an argument and
这是一个将闭包作为参数的iOS API
it runs that closure off the main queue.
它运行的是关闭主队列。
I's called NSURLSession, i's used for
我被称为NSURLSession，我是用来做的
getting the contents of URLs.
获取url的内容。
Now, you saw in our image view controller demo, so far,
现在，你们在我们的图像视图控制器演示中看到，到目前为止，
that we already know how to get the contents of URLs,
我们已经知道如何获取url的内容，
we just use data contents of.
我们只使用数据内容。
Remember, we said try data contents of.
记住，我们说的是尝试数据内容。
And it blocked, blocked the main queue while it went and
它阻塞了，阻塞了主队列
got that URL.
该URL。
So that's one way to do it.
这是一种方法。
But it kind of non-configurable.
但它是不可配置的。
What's cool about NSURLSession is,
NSURLSession最酷的是，
you see that argument there configuration.default?
看到这个参数了吗，默认值?
Well, you can change that configuration.
你可以改变这个构型。
For example, you could say, I'm gonna fetch this URL,
例如，你可以说，我要取回这个URL，
but don't fetch it over cellular.
但不要在细胞上取它。
Only fetch it if I happen to be on a Wi-Fi
只要我碰巧在wi - fi上，就去取它
network, for example.
例如,网络。
So you can configure how you want this fetching to happen.
因此，您可以配置您希望这种抓取发生的方式。
So it's kind of a more powerful way of fetching than
这是一种更强大的抓取方式
just saying data contents of.
只是说数据的内容。
And the way it works is you create an NSURLSession with a,
它的工作原理是用a来创建一个NSURLSession，
(this is an old slide, so it's just called URLSession and URL
not NSURL), but you create it with a certain configuration,
不是NSURL，但是你用一个特定的配置来创建它，
then you get the URL you want and then you call this
然后你得到你想要的URL然后你调用它
method dataTask(with: url) and closure.
方法dataTask(with:url)和闭包。
And what this does is it creates a dataTask object.
它所做的就是创建一个dataTask对象。
With that URL that you want to get, and when, and
有了你想要得到的URL，以及何时，以及
it goes off to fetch it, or it will in a minute.
它会去取它，或者它会在一分钟内。
And when you send it off to fetch it,
当你把它送去取的时候，
when it comes back it will call this closure and
当它回来的时候，它会调用这个闭包
this closure has three arguments.
这个闭包有三个参数。
The data it got from the URL, the NSURL or
它从URL中得到的数据，NSURL
the URL response, and then some error,
URL响应，然后是一些错误，
if some error happened trying to get it.
如果发生了一些错误。
So the, that closure, so this closure is interesting cuz it,
这个闭包，这个闭包很有趣，
the documentation will tell you,
文档会告诉你，
this closure does not run on the main queue.
这个闭包不会在主队列上运行。
So, that's a problem because if, (by the way, that resume,
所以，这是个问题，因为如果，
task.resume at the bottom,
的任务。简历在底部,
that's what actually causes it to go do the fetch),
这就是实际的取回的原因，
so the dataTask really doesn't do anything but
dataTask实际上什么都不做
create the task, and then when you say task.resume it goes
创建任务，然后当你说任务的时候。恢复它
off to fetch it on some other thread, doesn't block.
在别的线程上取它，不阻塞。
task.resume does not block obviously.
的任务。简历没有明显的阻碍。
So when the closure,
当关闭,
when the data is gotten and that closure is finally called
当数据得到，关闭最终被调用
on some other queue besides the main queue.
在主队列之外的其他队列上。
You wanna do some UI in there like you wanna show the image
你想在那里做一些UI，就像你想显示图像一样
that you just fetched or whatever.
你只是拿来了什么的。
And you can't do it because you're not on the main queue.
你不能这么做，因为你不在主队列上。
So, how do you fix that?
那么，如何解决这个问题呢?
You just put inside of this
你把它放在里面
closure that you put right here, another dispatch.
关闭这里，另一个调度。
Back to the main queue.
回到主队列。
DispatchQueue.main.async with a closure.
DispatchQueue.main。异步关闭。
And you put your UI stuff in there,
把UI放到这里，
now it's gonna happen back on the other, on the main queue.
现在它会发生在另一个，在主队列上。
So let's go through, I wanna show you the timing
让我们来回顾一下，我想告诉你们时间
of each of the steps of this code right here.
这个代码的每一个步骤。
So you can see what's happening, when.
所以你可以看到发生了什么，什么时候。
Because multithreading is really a lot about when, and
因为多线程确实很重要
it's the when that can confuse people when
这是什么时候会让人感到困惑的时候
they're doing multithreading.
他们正在做多线程。
So obviously, the first line of code is that let url,
很明显，第一行代码是，url，
get the url, so now I have the url.
获取url，现在我有了url。
Next, we're gonna create this dataTask.
接下来，我们要创建这个dataTask。
This line of code, line B there, returns immediately.
这一行代码，B行，立即返回。
Because all it does is create the dataTask,
因为它所做的就是创建dataTask，
it doesn't actually do anything.
它实际上什么都没做。
You pass the closure to it, but it's a non-escaping
你把它关了，但它是一个非逃避的
Closure, hold onto it, this data task thing holds onto it.
闭包，按住它，这个数据任务保存在它上面。
Then you do task resume, that also returns immediately.
然后你做任务简历，也会立即返回。
But on a different queue, it starts doing the fetch.
但在另一个队列上，它开始执行取回。
It starts trying to get the contents of that URL.
它开始尝试获取URL的内容。
But on some other queue, so
但在另一些队列上
that's why on this queue, this is the main queue presumably.
这就是为什么在这个队列中，这是主要的队列。
It is returning immediately,
这是立即返回,
task.resume returns immediately.
的任务。简历立即返回。
So that means that line H happens immediately right
这意味着直线H会立即发生
after task resume, boom the print firing,
任务恢复后，打印开火，
done firing off the request.
完成了请求。
But that's all we've done is fired
但这就是我们所做的一切
off the request at this point.
在这一点上，请停止。
The next line of code that's gonna happen after this one
下一行代码将在这个之后发生
is this one.
这是一个。
So after the URL contents come back,
URL内容回来之后，
now this closure is gonna execute.
现在这个闭包就会执行。
And so we're gonna have line c be executed.
所以我们要执行c行。
So a, b, g, and h, they executed boom, boom, boom,
所以a b g h，他们执行了boom,boom,boom，
boom, run right after each other, no delay.
砰，一声接着一声，毫不迟延。
Then there was a delay while we went and
我们去的时候有一个耽搁
got the URL content.
有内容的URL。
That could be a long delay.
这可能是一个很长的延迟。
That could be minute or more if it was a big file over
如果是一个大文件，那可能会是一分钟或更长时间
cellular or something like that.
细胞之类的。
So this line of code, c, you have to be careful.
所以这一行，c，你要小心。
It could happen much later, and by the time it happens,
它可能发生在很久以后，当它发生的时候，
you might not even care anymore.
你可能再也不在乎了。
If you had a really slow network and a big file,
如果你有一个很慢的网络和一个大文件，
by the time it came back, the user, they're like,
当它回来的时候，用户，他们说，
I don't even care about it.
我甚至不关心它。
So you, when you come back to line c right there,
当你回到c行，
you better check and make sure that you still even care.
你最好检查一下，确保你仍然关心。
Make sense?
有意义吗?
All right, next thing that happens is we wanna do some UI
接下来，我们要做一些UI
stuff with the data we got back.
我们取回的数据。
But of course to do that,
当然，
we have to dispatch to the main queue.
我们必须调度到主队列。
This line of code, line d,
这一行代码d，
also returns immediately because it's async dispatch.
还可以立即返回，因为它是异步调度。
All it's doing is putting that closure onto the main queue.
它所做的就是将关闭放到主队列上。
So this is the next line of code that executes.
这是执行的下一行代码。
Notice line e has not executed yet.
注意到e还没有执行。
Line f executes and it just says I did some stuff with
行f执行，它只是说我做了一些事情
the data, but the UI part hasn't happened yet.
数据，但UI部分还没有发生。
I put it on the queue, but it hasn't been executed yet
我把它放在队列上，但还没有执行
by the main queue.
在主要的队列中。
And then finally the UI stuff gets pulled off
最后，UI被取消了
the main queue and executed.
主队列并执行。
Did everyone understand that process?
大家都明白这个过程了吗?
So to summarize, its a, b, g, h, c, d, f, e.
总结一下，a,b,g,h,c,d,f,e。
Now this thing about this,
关于这个，
there's actually not necessarily exactly this way.
实际上并不是这样的。
Because when you dispatch things to the main queue from
因为当你将东西发送到主队列时
the main queue, they could run right away.
主队列，他们可以马上运行。
So it is possible that e could happen before f.
所以e可能在f之前发生。
But if this was on some other queue besides the main queue,
但如果这是在主队列之外的其他队列上，
it's very unlikely that e could happen before f.
在f之前，e很不可能发生。
But it even could then because the main queue has so
但它甚至可以，因为主要的队列是这样的
much priority that when you dispatch something onto it,
很重要的一点是，当你在上面发布一些东西时，
the system might immediately go and try and process it.
系统可能会立即尝试并处理它。
That's how high priority the main queue is.
这就是主队列的优先级。
So it's possible that e could happen before f.
所以e可能在f之前发生。
But I just want you to think conceptually that when you put
但我只是想让你们从概念上思考
something on the queue, you kind of put it on the queue,
在队列上，你把它放在队列上，
There might be other things on the main queue ahead of you.
在你前面的主要队列中可能还有其他的东西。
could happen later.
以后可能发生。
So definitely wouldn't run right away then.
所以肯定不会马上跑。
So that's the timing of multithreaded.
这就是多线程的时间。
So let's go back to our Cassini code and make it so
让我们回到卡西尼代码
that it uses these queues to stop blocking the main thread
它使用这些队列来停止阻塞主线程
and stop being all stuck like that.
不要再像那样被困住了。
To do this is actually remarkably simple.
这样做其实非常简单。
We're just gonna go back to our imageViewController,
我们将返回imageViewController，
this is the deadly line of code.
这是一条致命的代码。
I even put a comment in for
我甚至对此发表了评论
this line of code when I posted this last time so
这是我上次发布的代码
that you realize this is a terrible line of code.
你意识到这是一条可怕的代码。
This line of code, if this is in, from now on,
这行代码，如果这是在，从现在开始，
if you turn in homework with a line of code like this,
如果你用这样的代码来做作业，
you're gonna get major dings.
你会得到重大消息的。
Because one of the evaluation criteria now is gonna be no
因为其中一个评估标准是否定的
more blocking the main queue.
更多的阻塞主队列。
You cannot block the main queue.
不能阻塞主队列。
That's, that's an evaluation criteria of all the homework
这是所有家庭作业的评估标准
going forward and of your final project.
展望你的最终计划。
All right, so we have this terrible thing, and we can't
好吧，我们有一件可怕的事，我们不能
do this line of code like this cuz it blocks the main queue,
像这样的代码行，因为它阻塞了主队列，
so what are we gonna do?
那我们该怎么办?
We're just simply gonna put this call on some other queue.
我们只是把这个调用放到其他队列上。
And I'm gonna do that by just saying DispatchQueue.global,
我要用DispatchQueue.global来做，
I'm gonna get a global,
我将得到一个全局变量，
one of these global concurrent queues.
其中一个全局并发队列。
And it's asking me for the quality of service.
它要求我提供服务质量。
And the user initiated this request, but
用户发起了这个请求，但是
it's not interactive, so I'm gonna say userInitiated,
它不是交互式的，所以我说user发起，
the choices there.
的选择。
Now I've got the queue I want, and I'm just gonna
现在我有了我想要的队列，然后我就开始
asynchronously post this code that I wanna do,
异步地发布我想要做的代码，
this code that blocks, onto that global queue.
此代码将阻塞到全局队列。
And at some point, that global queue is going to allocate
在某个时候，全局队列将会分配
a thread and grab this closure off it and start running.
一根线，抓住这个关闭它并开始运行。
Now that's gonna happen pretty darn quick, but
这很快就会发生，但是
not necessarily instantly.
不一定立即。
So now I've solved the problem,
现在我已经解决了这个问题，
woo hoo, it's off the main queue.
哇，它不在主队列。
No longer blocking the main queue because this,
不再阻塞主队列，
which is executed on the main queue,
它在主队列上执行，
because all of this code is on the main queue.
因为所有这些代码都在主队列上。
We're executing all of our codes generally on
我们正在执行我们所有的代码
the main queue.
主要的队列。
This returns immediately.
这立即返回。
It's async, so it immediately returns, it just puts that
它是async，所以它会立即返回，它只是把它放在这里
closure on the queue and returns immediately.
关闭队列并立即返回。
So no blocking the main queue, excellent.
所以没有阻塞主队列，很好。
But you notice I got this little error here.
但是你注意到我在这里犯了一个小错误。
Let's take a look at it, what's that thing?
让我们来看看，那是什么?
Yeah, reference to self inside a closure.
是的，在闭包里提到self。
You have to explicitly put self so
你必须明确地把自己放出来
that you think about memory cycles.
你想到的是记忆周期。
And indeed, there is a bad memory cycle here.
事实上，这里有一个糟糕的记忆周期。
Because this closure, if you remember, this is happening
因为这个闭包，如果你还记得，这是发生的
because I clicked on Saturn or Cassini or Earth.
因为我点击了土星或卡西尼或地球。
And it went off, created an ImageViewController for me,
它关闭了，为我创建了一个ImageViewController，
and that ImageView Controller is being put on screen and
这个imageviewcontroller被放到屏幕上
it's going off to fetch this thing.
它要去取这个东西。
Now what if the user is like, I'm tired of waiting for
如果用户喜欢，我已经厌倦了等待
that Earth image, and they hit back, and go click on Saturn.
这是地球的图像，他们回击，然后点击土星。
When they hit back,
当他们反击,
what's supposed to happen to that ImageViewController?
ImageViewController会发生什么?
Anyone?
有人知道吗?
>> It's supposed to leave the heap, okay.
Because it was under navigation controllers on
因为它在导航控制器的下面
the top and I hit back.
上面和我打回去了。
Whoo, toss it out, but can it leave?
哇，把它扔出去，但它能离开吗?
No, because this closure is keeping it in
不，因为这个闭合是保持它的
the heap even though I don't want this any more.
即使我不再需要它了。
I went back because I'm now I'm going over to see
我回去是因为我现在要去看
Saturn instead of Earth, so
土星代替了地球，所以
I don't even want this Earth thing any more.
我再也不想要这个地球了。
So this is a bad kind of memory cycle cuz this is gonna
这是一种很糟糕的记忆周期
keep that ImageViewController in memory, so that's bad.
将ImageViewController保存在内存中，这样就不好了。
So this doesn't want to do this, so
所以这个不需要这么做
we're gonna fix this one using weak self.
我们要用弱的self来解决这个问题。
By the way, you know, I showed that you can do,
顺便说一下，你知道，我证明了你能做到，
weak weak self equals self.
虚弱的自我等同于自我。
But I'm a personally a fan of when you're using weak on
但当你用弱的时候，我是一个喜欢的人
self to just say weak self.
自我只是说脆弱的自己。
And all that does is inside of this closure, it make
它所做的一切都是在这个闭包内完成的
self be an optional version of itself, cuz it's weak now.
self是它自己的可选版本，因为它现在很弱。
So that means I have to do this because if I do finally
这意味着我必须这样做，因为如果我最后做了
come back from this closure and the person has hit back,
从这个封闭性回来，这个人回击了，
then the ImageViewController is gonna have left the heap.
然后ImageViewController会离开堆。
And so self with be nil, perfect, exactly what I want.
所以self是nil，完美，正是我想要的。
And if self is nil and I do this little optional chaining,
如果self是nil我做的是可选的链接，
then this whole line of code is not gonna happen,
然后这整行代码就不会发生了，
exactly what I want.
正是我想要的。
I do not want to create an image out of that
我不想创建一个图像
information that came back.
回来的信息。
Because that ImageViewController has
因为,ImageViewController
left the heap.
离开了堆。
So here I've broken this memory cycle beautifully here.
这里我把这个记忆周期写得很好。
Now, this does beg the question,
这就提出了一个问题，
surprised no one has raised their hand.
没有人举手表示惊讶。
How do I interrupt this closure?
如何中断这个关闭?
When I hit back, and that ImageViewController goes away,
当我点击返回时，ImageViewController消失了，
and I'm not interested in Earth any more,
我对地球不再感兴趣，
I'm still finishing the fetch, of Earth.
我还在完成我的取回。
And the answer is, you can't stop a closure
答案是，你不能停止关闭
that's been put on a queue, you cannot stop it.
它被放在一个队列上，你无法阻止它。
The only way it can stop is if it quits itself.
它能停止的唯一方法就是它自己退出。
So it could be looking at some global state to see if it's
因此，它可能正在研究一些全球国家，看看它是否存在
still relevant.
仍然相关。
And if it sees, I'm not relevant anymore,
如果它看到了，我就不再重要了，
it could return.
它可以返回。
So if it was doing some long running thing.
所以如果它在做一些长时间运行的事情。
Could do that.
可以这样做。
Or you can use something like NSUrlSession
或者你可以使用像NSUrlSession这样的东西
which is really smart about going and getting URLs.
这对于获取url非常聪明。
And it knows how to be interrupted and
它知道如何被打断
all the things like that.
诸如此类的东西。
So you could do something a little smarter than just this
所以你可以做一些比这更聪明的事情
one line of code.
一行代码。
But once this goes on the queue, it, it's gonna run.
但一旦它进入队列，它就会运行。
So it's up to it to decide not to run.
所以决定不跑是由它决定的。
So we fix that problem of it, but
所以我们解决了这个问题，但是
there's still more problems in here.
还有更多的问题。
What happens if this takes a minute,
如果这需要一分钟，会发生什么呢?
or ten minutes because slow network or whatever.
或者十分钟，因为慢速网络之类的。
And we get back and in the meantime,
我们回来了，同时，
someone called this on my ImageViewController.
有人在我的ImageViewController上调用了这个。
Now, our Cassini can't do that, but
现在，我们的卡西尼号不能这么做，但是
you could imagine an app that
你可以想象一个应用程序
would be showing something in the ImageViewController.
会在ImageViewController中显示一些东西。
And then you click on something in
然后你点击一些东西
the ImageViewController itself and it shows a different URL.
ImageViewController本身，它显示了一个不同的URL。
So someone calls this.
所以有人叫这个。
If I call this again, it's gonna go down here and
如果我再调用一次，它就会向下延伸
fetchImage again, which is here, and it's gonna dispatch
fetchImage，它在这里，它会发送
another closure off to go get the new image.
另一个封闭的地方去获取新的图像。
So now there's two closures out there fetching.
现在有两个闭包取回。
Now what happen when the first one comes back?
当第一个回来的时候，会发生什么呢?
What do I wanna do with that image?
我要怎么处理这个图像?
Ignore it.
忽略它。
Because the person said they want a new one.
因为那个人说他们想要一个新的。
So I better put something in here after this comes back to
所以我最好在后面加一些东西
see if I even care about that anymore, which is easy.
看看我是否还关心这个，这很简单。
I could just say for example image == self?.imageURL.
比如image = = self。imageurl。
So I'm sorry url == self?.imageURL.
抱歉，url = = self ?。imageurl。
So I'm just gonna look at this url, which is right here,
我要看看这个url，在这里，
got captured by this closure.
被这个闭包捕获。
This closure has captured this url.
这个闭包捕获了这个url。
I'm just gonna check if that url equals whatever
我将检查这个url是否等于什么
our current url is.
我们当前的url。
And if, if I'm not there, then it's okay.
如果我不在那里，那就没事了。
It's gonna be nil. So if I can equal nil, and
它会是零。如果我可以等于nil
there we go.
好了。
So here I just put a little test in there to make
我在这里做了一个小测试
sure that I'm still interested in that URL.
当然，我仍然对那个URL感兴趣。
Can everyone understand what's going on here,
大家都能理解这里发生了什么吗?
where url = imageURL,
url = imageURL,
this is a constant, a constant that got captured here.
这是一个常数，在这里得到了一个常数。
So i's always gonna be the URL that we went and
所以我一直是我们的URL
got the contents of.
得到的内容。
Ther's yet another problem here.
这里还有一个问题。
Can anyone tell me another problem with this code,
谁能告诉我这个代码的另一个问题，
obvious problem?
明显的问题吗?
I just showed you in the slides.
我刚刚给你们看了幻灯片。
This right here,
这里,
self?.image is gonna call this code down here.
自我?。图像会调用下面这里的代码。
That's gonna do all kinds of UI stuff.
它会做各种UI的事情。
It's gonna set the scrollView's content size,
它会设置scrollView的内容大小，
size of the imageView, size of the imageView's image.
imageView的大小，imageView的图像的大小。
This is all UI stuff.
这是所有UI的东西。
Where does that need to happen?
这种情况需要发生在哪里?
On the main queue.
在主队列。
And is this on the main queue right here?
这个在主队列上吗?
No, this is on this queue over here, this global queue,
不，这是在这个队列上，这个全局队列，
userInitiated global queue.
userInitiated全球队列。
That's where this is all happening, so
这就是一切发生的地方
that's not the main queue.
那不是主要的队列。
So that is illegal.
这是非法的。
That's gonna cause all kinds of weird behavior in your app
这将会在你的应用中造成各种奇怪的行为
if you do that.
如果你这样做。
But easily fitched, fixed,
但容易惠誉、固定
we'll just ditch DispatchQueue.main.async and
我们只要沟DispatchQueue.main。异步和
put this back on the main queue.
把这个放回主队列。
Now what's really cool about this syntax,
这个语法很酷，
I guess you would say, of doing these things is
我猜你会说，做这些事情
it looks very much logically like normal code.
它在逻辑上看起来很像普通代码。
Right, it's almost just like if thens or whatever.
对，几乎就像这样。
However, you do have to understand that when you do
然而，当你这样做的时候，你必须明白这一点
a dispatch like this, that's gonna happen asynchronously.
这样的调度，是异步发生的。
It's gonna happen in a different time
它会在不同的时间发生
than the rest of this code.
比剩下的代码要多。
Same thing with this one.
这个也一样。
This is gonna happen a little different time.
这将会发生一些不同的时间。
Now of course, things
当然,事情
that you put on the main queue tend to run pretty quick.
你放在主队列上的速度会很快。
But even so, you just have to be cognizant of the fact that
但即便如此，你还是要认识到这一点
even though it looks like this line of code is gonna happen,
即使看起来这一行代码会发生，
then this line, then this line, then this line,
然后这条线，然后这条线，这条线，
then this line, it's not gonna happen.
然后这条线，它不会发生。
It's gonna happen more like the slides, right,
它会更像幻灯片，对吧，
where things happen a little bit out of order there
哪里发生了一点变化
because things are happening asynchronously.
因为事情是异步发生的。
Async means asynchronously, out of time,
异步意味着异步，超时，
right, different, not lined up in time.
对，不同，没有及时排队。
Everybody got that?
大家都明白了吗?
Let's see if that fixes all our problems.
让我们看看这是否解决了我们所有的问题。
So remember, here we have no image.
记住，这里没有图像。
By the way, this is a terrible problem right here where this
顺便说一下，这是一个很严重的问题
comes up blank.
出现空白。
And I actually mentioned last week that I was gonna
上周我还提到了
make it extra credit for you to figure out how to not
让它额外的学分，让你知道如何不
make this blank in your calculator, have it
在你的计算器上做这个空白，有它
come up with the calculator instead of an empty graph.
用计算器来代替一个空的图。
But I decided instead I'm gonna show you how to
但我还是决定告诉你怎么做
do it today.
今天做。
That's why I didn't
这就是为什么我没有
make it extra credit in the assignment.
在作业中增加学分。
But anyway, so here's the detail.
但无论如何，这是细节。
We haven't picked an image so it's blank.
我们没有选图像，所以它是空的。
Now I'm gonna go back.
现在我要回去了。
Here's our Cassini viewController.
这是我们卡西尼viewController。
Now I'm gonna pick Earth, and it's loading up, but
现在我要选择地球，它正在加载，但是
I changed my mind.
我改变主意了。
Saturn, changed my mind.
土星、改变了我的想法。
I can change my mind now because
我现在可以改变主意了
those things are being fetched in some other thread.
这些东西在其他线程中被获取。
Now if I wait long enough, they get it and return it.
如果我等得够久，他们就会得到并归还。
So here I am.
所以我在这里。
I have Cassini here.
我在这里有卡西尼。
If I go back and hit Earth, again, I give up.
如果我回到地球，再次，我放弃。
Saturn, I'll wait, and we'll see if we get Saturn.
土星，我等一下，看看我们能不能得到土星。
By the way, Saturn, this is kind of a weird, I don't think
顺便说一下，土星，这有点奇怪，我不认为
Cassini took this photo here, this picture of the people.
卡西尼拍了这张照片，照片上的人。
But wait a minute, look at that, there's Saturn.
但是等一下，看看这个，土星。
One thing about this app, though, that's kind of bad
关于这个应用，有一点很糟糕
is I click on this and I get this white screen.
我点击这个，得到这个白色的屏幕。
Especially on a big image like this one we get this white
尤其是像这样的大图像，我们得到了白色
screen, it's white screen, it's white screen.
屏幕，它是白色的屏幕，白色的屏幕。
It's like what's happening in this app?
这就像在这个应用程序里发生了什么?
I don't even understand what's going on.
我甚至不知道发生了什么。
It would be really cool if I could give the user some
如果我能给用户一些，那就太酷了
feedback about what's happening.
反馈关于发生了什么。
Now this feedback might be something that says loading
这个反馈可能是加载
dot dot dot dot or something.
点·点或其他点。
But a really cool feedback when you're waiting for
但当你在等待的时候，会有一个很酷的反馈
something is a spinning, a little spinner.
有些东西是旋转的，有点旋转。
Have you seen those spinners?
你见过那些纺纱工吗?
A lot of apps have this where there's a little spinner.
很多应用都有一个小转轮。
So let's add a spinner to our app so
让我们在app中添加一个spinner
that when we click here, it's a little thing spinning
当我们点击这里，它是一个旋转的小东西
until an image appears, and then it goes away.
直到图像出现，然后它就消失了。
That turns out to be incredible easy to do,
这很容易做到，
because that's a common thing to want to do is to give
因为这是一件很常见的事情
the user feedback.
用户反馈。
Yes, I heard you and I'm working on it, but
是的，我听到了，我正在努力
I don't have it yet.
我还没有。
How do we do that?
怎么做呢?
Let's go back to our storyboard.
让我们回到故事板。
And this is where we're gonna wanna do that is on this
这就是我们要做的
viewController right here.
viewController。
This is where our scrollView is with our little
这是我们的滚动视图与我们的小的地方
imageView in there.
imageView。
And what we can do is just go over over here and
我们可以做的就是把它放在这里
get an object.
得到一个对象。
It's called an Activity Indicator View.
它被称为活动指示器视图。
Here it is right here, view an Activity Indicator View.
在这里，查看活动指示器视图。
And I'm just gonna drag this into my UI,
我把这个拖拽到UI中，
right in the middle.
在中间。
Now what I just did there was a very bad thing.
现在我所做的是一件非常糟糕的事情。
It looked fine, but it's very bad.
看起来很好，但很糟糕。
And it's a little subtle as to why it's bad, so
这是很微妙的，为什么它是坏的，所以
let's investigate this one in depth why this was bad that
让我们深入调查一下为什么这很糟糕
I dragged that in there.
我把它拖进去了。
And the way we gonna see that it's bad is by bringing
我们可以通过引入来发现它是不好的
out for the first time this document outline.
这是第一次，这个文档大纲。
This little thing in the lower left which I told you we were
在左下角的这个小东西，我告诉过你们
gonna talk about and here we are talking about it.
我们来谈谈这个问题。
This is everything that's in our storyboard in
这是故事板中的所有内容
outline form, in kind of text form.
提纲形式，以文本形式。
And when we do this,
当我们这样做的时候，
we look down here at this Activity Indicator View.
我们向下看这个活动指示器视图。
By the way, if you select something here,
顺便说一下，如果你选择了一些东西，
it'll select it here and vice versa.
它会在这里选择，反之亦然。
So this is selected, so it's showing it here.
这是选择的，所以它在这里显示。
And you see how these things, this is all the views, this is
你可以看到这些，这是所有的视图，这是
the top level view, that's the view var in the controller.
顶层视图，这是控制器中的视图var。
Then here is that scrollView that we made, and
这里是我们做的scrollView
then here is the indicator view.
然后这里是指示器视图。
We see how these are indented,
我们看到这些是如何缩进的，
that means they are subviews of each other.
这意味着它们是彼此的子视图。
So we made the gray activity indicator
所以我们做了灰色活动指示器
a subview of our Scroll View, we do not want that here.
我们的滚动视图的子视图，我们不希望在这里。
We want our Scroll View scrolling around our image,
我们希望滚动视图在我们的图像周围滚动，
we don't want it scrolling our indicator around.
我们不希望它滚动我们的指示器。
We want the indicator to stay in the middle.
我们希望指标保持在中间。
We don't want it to be a subview of Scroll View,
我们不希望它是滚动视图的子视图，
we want it to be a sibling.
我们希望它是一个兄弟姐妹。
We want them both to be at the same level,
我们希望它们都处于相同的水平，
one in front of the other.
一个在另一个前面。
And we can do that just by picking this up right here,
我们可以这样做，
and moving it to the same level as Scroll View.
并将其移动到与滚动视图相同的级别。
Now that's very hard to do in here because any time you try
这在这里很难，因为任何时候都可以
to pick this up and move it, it's always gonna wanna try
把它捡起来，然后移动它，它总是想尝试
and drop into a subview or a superview of something, so
然后进入子视图或超视图
it's always gonna grab on to it.
它总是会抓住它。
But in this document outline it's very easy.
但在这个文档大纲中，它很简单。
You can just pick it up and move it there.
你可以把它捡起来，然后移动它。
So when you do these activity indicator views in your future
所以当你在未来做这些活动指标的时候
apps and in your final project,
应用程序和最终项目，
make sure you don't accidentally make it a sub
确保你不会不小心把它变成潜艇
view of something that you drag it onto.
看你把它拖到的东西。
If it what you intend.
如果你想要的话。
Notice also the order matters here.
注意这里的顺序很重要。
This is the sub views in their, in order, and
这是它们的子视图，按顺序排列
remember that sub view sub zero is in the back, and
记住子视图下标0在后面
all the other ones are in the front.
其他的都在前面。
So we obviously want this activity indicator to
我们显然想要这个活动指示器
be in the front, in front of everything.
在前面，在所有的前面。
All right, so that was that.
好了，就是这样。
Now what we wanna do is we want to wire this activity
现在我们要做的是把这个活动连接起来
indicator right here up to our code.
在这里显示我们的代码。
Why? Because we have to tell it to
为什么?因为我们必须告诉它
start running.
开始运行。
Or actually even before we do that,
甚至在我们开始之前，
let's configure it a little bit.
我们来配置一下。
We've got it right here, we can inspect it.
我们把它放在这里，我们可以检查它。
Here's the inspector of it, see Activity Indicator View.
这是它的检查器，看活动指示器视图。
It looks kind of small to me for this big view.
在我看来，这一大图看起来有点小。
So I'm gonna switch to a different kind
所以我要换一种
which is the Large White.
这是白色的。
But I don't actually want it to be white
但我并不希望它是白色的
because the background is white.
因为背景是白色的。
So I'm gonna change its color to be, Iet's say blue.
我要改变它的颜色，设为蓝色。
So this can be large and blue.
所以这个可以是大而蓝色。
Also, every time I stop animating it, I want it to
而且，每次我停止动画的时候，我都想要它
hide itself, because I don't want it to be stopped
躲起来，因为我不想让它停下来
spinning, sitting there showing.
旋转,坐在那里显示。
Any time it stops I want it to disappear.
任何时候它停止我想要它消失。
Then if I start it again, it'll reappear.
如果我重新开始，它就会重新出现。
So that's what this button is.
这就是这个按钮。
This here animating would mean that it would come up
这里的动画意味着它会上升
animating, but
动画,但
I'm gonna turn it on any time I go do a background fetch.
我要在任何时候把它打开，做后台取回。
So I don't want it to come up with this view animating
所以我不希望它出现在这个视图中
already.
了。
That's what those all mean.
这就是它们的意思。
To turn it on I need to talk to it, so
我需要和它谈谈，所以
I need an outlet to it.
我需要一个出口。
So I'm just gonna control drag from it, just like any other
所以我只需要control拖动，就像其他的一样
outlet we would make to a button or whatever.
我们会对一个按钮或其他东西进行输出。
Here it is.
在这儿。
I'm gonna call it a spinner, that's what I like to call
我把它命名为spinner，这就是我喜欢调用的
my UI activity indicators, spinner.
我的UI活动指示器，spinner。
There's my spinner outlet right there.
这是我的spinner outlet。
All I need to do here is turn this thing on whenever I
我在这里要做的就是把这个东西打开
go off to another thread to do something.
到另一个线程去做某事。
So here's where I go off to another thread to do
这是我到另一个线程去做的地方
something, so I'm just gonna say spinner.startAnimating.
有些东西，所以我要说的是spinner.startAnimating。
And that's gonna start it spinning.
然后开始旋转。
It's gonna unhide it, if it was hidden, and
如果它被隐藏了，它就会把它隐藏起来
start it spinning.
启动它旋转。
Question?
问题吗?
>> Animated just make thatlittle blue thing go round
It just makes it spin just like all spinners.
它就像所有的纺纱器一样旋转。
and round.
和圆。
>> Yeah, well, when I inspected it over here.
And I did, and I didn't click this button Animating,
我没有点击这个按钮动画，
that just means it doesn't start out animating.
这意味着它不会开始动画。
I have to start it in code, that's what this means.
我必须从代码开始，这就是它的意思。
If I turn this on,
打开这个，
then as soon as my app came up it would be animating,
一旦我的应用程序出现，它就会是动画，
which I don't want that.
我不想那样。
I don't want it to start animating until I do this
我不想让它开始动画，直到我这么做
dispatch onto some other queue,
分派到其他队列，
that's when I want it to start animating.
那是我想让它开始动画的时候。
Now, you might imagine that the place to stop animating it
现在，你可以想象这个地方停止动画
might be right here.
可能是在这里。
spinner.stopAnimating, but and this would kinda make sense.
微调控制项。停止动画，但这是有意义的。
Because you know, I went off to go get this image and
因为你知道，我去取了这个图像
it came back, and I set the image.
它回来了，我设置了图像。
Now I can stop animating.
现在我可以停止动画了。
But actually I don't wanna do that here.
但实际上我不想在这里做。
And that is because I wanna stop animating
那是因为我想停止动画
anytime the image is set.
任何时候图像都设置好了。
If an image is set in my image view controller,
如果图像在图像视图控制器中设置，
I wanna stop animating.
我想停止动画。
I don't care how it got set.
我不在乎它是怎么设置的。
If it got set from my thing coming back, that's good.
如果它从我回来的东西中得到了集合，那很好。
If someone set it by saying,
如果有人说，
image URL equals like a local URL, I wanna stop then too.
图像URL等于本地URL，我也想停止。
So I'm gonna put it down here an image.
我要把它放在这里。
Here's where we set our image.
这是我们设置图像的地方。
This is the set part of it.
这是它的集合。
And I'm just gonna say down here, stopAnimating.
我要在这里写上，stopAnimating。
So, any time my image is set I'm gonna stop animating cuz
所以，每当我的图像被设置时，我就停止动画
it would make no sense if the image was there and
如果图像在那里，那就没有意义了
the thing was animating.
的动画。
That would never make sense for
这是没有意义的
an image to be showing, and it to animate at the same time.
一个要显示的图像，同时它也可以动画。
Because animating
因为动画
this thing means I'm waiting for an image.
这意味着我在等待一个图像。
Got it?
明白了吗?
Touch it, that's all you have to do to do the spinners,
触摸它，这就是你要做的所有的旋转器，
they're super, super simple.
他们是超级,超级简单。
They only makes sense when you're doing things in other
当你在做其他事情的时候，它们才有意义
threads with the spinner.
线程与转轮。
Cuz if you're me, if you're not doing something in another
如果你是我，如果你不在另一个地方做什么
thread then why would you?
那你为什么要这么做?
See, now look.
看,现在看来。
This came up, it's blank but it's not spinning
它是空的，但不是旋转的
because I haven't asked for anything yet.
因为我还没有要求什么。
So I'll go back here and I'll ask for Earth.
所以我要回到这里，我要求地球。
It says nil while doing Optional value.
它在做可选值时表示nil。
That's not bad.
这是不坏。
What happened here?
这里发生了什么?
Ahh, yeah, good one.
啊,是的,不错。
All right, so this crashed.
好了，这就崩溃了。
Why did this crash?
为什么这个崩溃?
Why did we have a problem here?
为什么会有问题呢?
And the answer here is that when I set
答案是，当我设置的时候
this image I was in prepare.
这张照片是我准备的。
And when I'm in prepare, my outlets are not set.
当我在准备的时候，我的销售点没有设置。
So I need to optional chain that right there.
所以我需要可选的链。
So this crash, you'll get it yourself a lot,
所以这次碰撞，你会得到很多，
where you prepare something and crash.
在你准备东西和碰撞的地方。
It crashes during prepare because you try to set
它在准备过程中崩溃，因为你试图设置
your outlets.
你的商店。
Now, this is fine for the spinner not to be set, and
现在，这对于spinner没有设置，还有
I'm setting the image because I never would have started it
我在设置图像，因为我永远不会启动它
in this condition anyway.
在这种情况下。
So all is well just to ignore setting the image when I'm
所以，当我在做的时候，一切都很好
preparing.
准备。
Everybody got that one?
大家都明白了吗?
You all have that, hundreds of times in your iOS careers
在你的iOS职业生涯中，你有几百次这样的情况
where you have some code that you'll prepare,
你需要准备一些代码，
execute that uses an outlet.
执行使用一个outlet。
All right, so let's go back now, we hit Earth.
好了，现在我们回到地球。
See it's spinning.
看到它的旋转。
As soon as the image gets put in here, it stops spinning,
一旦图像放到这里，它就停止旋转，
all right, it's gone.
好了,走了。
Okay, back here, spinning.
好了,回到这里,旋转。
Yeah, we don't want it.
是的，我们不想要。
Let's go here, skip it here.
我们到这里，跳过这里。
Now, the last thing I wanna do is this thing where,
现在，我想做的最后一件事是，
when the thing starts up it starts up blank.
当事情开始的时候，它就开始空白了。
All right, it starts blank because it's on the detail.
它开始是空的，因为它在细节上。
And I don't want it on the detail
我不想详细说明
when there's no image URL there.
当没有图像URL的时候。
I want it to start up here if, when I first start.
我想让它从这里开始，如果，当我第一次开始。
All right, so how do I do that?
好吧，那我该怎么做呢?
I'm gonna do that using the split view controllers.
我要用分屏视图控制器。
If we go look at our storyboard here.
如果我们看一下故事板。
I'm gonna use the delegate of this split
我要用这个分叉的委托
view controller right here.
视图控制器。
Because this split view controller asks the delegate,
因为分屏视图控制器要求委托，
would you like to do the job of collapsing the primary
你想做的是在初选中崩溃吗
view, the secondary view controller rather,
视图，二级视图控制器，
you know the detail, on top of the master?
你知道细节，在大师的上面?
Okay, so it's gonna give me the opportunity to do that.
它会给我机会来做这个。
And what I'm gonna do is, if there's no image URL in there,
我要做的是，如果没有图像URL，
I'm gonna say I did it but I'm not gonna do anything.
我说我做到了，但我什么也不想做。
And that's gonna cause it not to collapse the detail
这样就不会破坏细节
on top of the master.
在大师之上。
Now, I need to have one of my view controllers be the split
现在，我需要有一个视图控制器
view controller's delegate.
视图控制器的委托。
And I can't really have it be this one right here
我不能把它变成这个
because this one comes and goes.
因为这一个来了又去。
This is the Image View Controller. It gets created
这是图像视图控制器。它被创造的
when it's segued to and when you go away, it stops.
当它被segue到，当你离开时，它就停止了。
You go throw it out of the heap.
你把它扔出堆。
So I can't have my split view controller's delegate thrown
所以我不能把分屏视图控制器的委托扔出去
out of the heap all the time, so
一直从堆里出来，所以
instead I'm going to have this view controller be my split
相反，我要让这个视图控制器是我的拆分
view controller's delegate.
视图控制器的委托。
So here we go.
所以我们走。
Here's my CassiniViewController.
这是我的CassiniViewController。
Now where is a good place to set yourself as your own split
现在，哪里有好地方让你自己分裂
view controller's delegate?
视图控制器的委托吗?
You could probably do it in view and
你可以在视图中做
load and that would work.
load和that would work。
But I think a better,
但我觉得更好，
safer place to do it is awakeFromNib.
更安全的地方是awakeFromNib。
Cuz awakeFromNib if you remember from from
如果你还记得的话
the ViewController life cycle is called really early
ViewController的生命周期被称为非常早
in the game.
在游戏中。
So if I wanna set my own splitViewController's
如果我想设置自己的splitViewController
delegate to myself, delegate.
对自己委托,委托。
This is really early time to do it.
现在还为时尚早。
Now notice here that I'm taking my
注意这里
own splitViewController which might be nil,
自己的splitViewController，可能是nil，
because I might not be in a splitViewController.
因为我可能不在splitViewController中。
And I'm setting its delegate to myself.
我把它委托给自己。
Remember, every ViewController has this bar
记住，每个ViewController都有这个条
splitViewController which is the splitViewController,
splitViewController,splitViewController，
it's in if it is in one.
它在一个里面。
And so I'm getting an error here,
这里有个错误，
anyone know what this error is?
有人知道这个错误是什么吗?
Nobody?
没有人吗?
It says that you can not assign a CassiniViewController
它说你不能分配一个CassiniViewController
to be a UISplitViewControllerDelegate.
UISplitViewControllerDelegate。
You can't make this equal this, that's because this is
你不能让它等于这个，因为这是
CassiniViewController is not a UISplitViewDelegate.
CassiniViewController不是一个UISplitViewDelegate。
UISplitViewControllerDelegate.
UISplitViewControllerDelegate。
We have to say that it's a UISplitViewControllerDelegate.
我们不得不说,这是一个UISplitViewControllerDelegate。
Okay, once we say that, that resolves this error.
好的，一旦我们这么说，它就解决了这个错误。
All the methods in that protocol are optional.
该协议中的所有方法都是可选的。
So, we've satisfied the protocol,
我们已经满足了这个协议，
which is kinda weird.
这是有点奇怪的。
But now we can implement any of the ones we want.
但是现在我们可以实现我们想要的任何一个。
Here's a trick for you.
这里有个小窍门。
If you want, if you're a delegate and
如果你想，如果你是一名代表
you wanna find out what methods are,
你想知道方法是什么，
just start typing the name of the class.
只要开始键入类的名称即可。
So here's splitView and
这是栏
here's all the splitViewControllerDelegates.
这是所有splitViewControllerDelegates。
You have to have done this part first.
你必须先做这部分。
You have to say you're a delegate first.
你必须先说你是代表。
Once you do that, it's gonna show all these, right,
一旦你这样做了，它就会显示出所有这些，对吧?
these are all the things splitViewDelegate can do.
这些都是splitViewDelegate可以做的事情。
And we want this one right here at the top.
我们要把这个放在上面。
CollapseSecondary onto primary.
CollapseSecondary到初选。
So I'm gonna double-click that.
我要双击它。
I'll show you these arguments a little easier to see if I do
我会给你们看一些更容易看的论证
this.
这一点。
That and then this one.
然后这个。
So this splitViewControllerDelegate
所以这splitViewControllerDelegate
method has three arguments, one is the sender,
方法有三个参数，一个是sender，
that's the splitViewController asking you.
这是splitViewController问你。
Here, it's asking me please collapse
在这里，它在问我是否可以折叠
this secondaryViewController, that's a detail onto
这个第二个视图控制器，这是一个细节
this primaryViewController that's the master.
这个primaryViewController是master。
So this what happens when we first start up, a blank detail
这就是我们第一次开始的时候，一个空白的细节
gets put on top of the master, and we don't want that.
把它放在大师的上面，我们不希望这样。
But we only don't want that if that detail is blank.
但我们不希望这个细节是空白的。
So I'm gonna go here and say if the PrimaryViewController
我要在这里输入，如果PrimaryViewController
is myself, because if the PrimaryViewController is not
如果主视图控制器不是
myself, then the things are gone weird here,
我自己，然后事情变得奇怪了，
but it should be.
但它应该。
So I'm gonna say if the PrimaryViewController.conte-
所以我想说如果PrimaryViewController.conte -
nts, because I might be in navigation controller equals
nts，因为我可能在导航控制器中
myself, remember contents is this thing down here.
我自己，记住内容是下面这个东西。
So, I'm doing that there.
我在这里做这个。
Then I say if I can let the ImageViewController equal
然后我说，如果我能让ImageViewController等于
the secondaryViewController, that's the detail.
第二个视图控制器，这是detail。
It's this argument right here.
就是这个参数。
It can pass to me,
它可以传给我，
it's the thing that is asking me to collapse on top of it.
这就是让我崩溃的原因。
SecondaryViewController as an ImageViewController.
SecondaryViewController ImageViewController。
And again here, I wanna do contents.
在这里，我想做内容。
So that's inside the NavigationController.
这是导航控制器的内部。
But that's not all.
但这还不是全部。
It's not just if I have an ImageViewController being
它不只是如果我有一个ImageViewController存在
asked to collapse on top of me.
被要求在我身上崩溃。
But I wanna make sure that that IVC's imageURL.
但我要确保IVC的imageURL。
Equals nil.
等于零。
So if splitViewController's asking me to collapse
如果splitViewController要求我崩溃
an ImageViewController that has a blank image,
一个有空白图像的ImageViewController，
I'm going to return true to say, yep, I did it.
我将返回true，说，是的，我做到了。
But I'm not actually going to do anything.
但我不会做任何事情。
Because I don't want that to happen.
因为我不想让这种事情发生。
So I'm kinda faking out this splitViewController there.
我在这里假装这个splitViewController。
Otherwise I'm gonna return false, which means, no,
否则我将返回false，这意味着，不，
I couldn't do this collapse, so you do it.
我不能这么做，所以你这么做。
Now the splitViewController will do it itself.
splitViewController本身也会这样做。
So it's kinda funky, but I just wanted to show you this,
这有点怪，但我只是想给你们看这个，
to show you that there are a little more complicated ways
为了向你们展示，有一些更复杂的方法
to do things then I sometimes show.
为了做事情，我有时会表现出来。
But look what happened.
但是看发生了什么事。
I ran and I did not get that blank VieController.
我跑了，没有得到那个空白的控制。
Because I told splitViewController
因为我告诉splitViewController
that I collapsed it on there, but I didn't really so
我把它倒在那里了，但我真的没有
it did nothing.
它什么也没做。
But if I click on one now the image url is not nil and so
但是如果我点击一个，图像url不是nil
it did do the collapse for me.
它确实为我崩溃了。
All right, so that's it.
好了，就是这样。
Let's get back to our slides and do our last topic here.
让我们回到幻灯片，在这里做最后一个主题。
Which is our text field.
这就是我们的文本字段。
So I'm just gonna throw in text field in here,
我在这里输入文本框，
cuz you're, it's going to be included in our next demo and
因为你是，它将会被包括在我们的下一个demo中
in your next assignment, it's a pretty easy little class,
在下一个作业中，这是一个很简单的课程，
UITextField.
UITextField。
It's very similar to UILabel.
它和UILabel非常相似。
The difference is it's editable.
区别在于它是可编辑的。
UILabel, if you touch on it, nothing happens.
UILabel，如果你触碰它，什么也不会发生。
But you do UITextField, if you touch on it,
但是你做UITextField，如果你接触它，
a little blinking cursor happens and the keyboard will
一个闪烁的光标发生了，键盘就会
come up from the bottom, and you can use your thumbs and
从底部上来，你可以用你的拇指和
type, or, if you have an iPad with a physical keyboard,
输入，或者，如果你有一个带有物理键盘的iPad，
you could type or whatever.
你可以打字或者随便什么。
That's all the UITextField is.
这就是UITextField。
Now because it's editable, it's got some little
因为它是可编辑的，它有一些
intricacies that are quite a bit different than UILabel.
与UILabel有很大不同的复杂之处。
It still has things like attributed text,
它还有一些属性，
and you can set the font, and all these things,
你可以设置字体，以及所有这些，
because it's very much like a UILabel in that way.
因为它很像UILabel。
But there's this keyboard, okay, when you are in
但这是键盘，当你进来的时候
UITextField and you touch on it, it brings up a keyboard.
UITextField，你触摸它，它会弹出一个键盘。
So how does that keyboard show and not show?
那么这个键盘是怎么显示出来的呢?
Well, the keyboard shows any time, any view,
键盘可以显示任何时间，任何视图，
in the view hierarchy, becomes the first responder or
在视图层次结构中，成为第一个响应器
what's called the first responder.
所谓的第一反应者。
And the first responder means it wants to be the thing that
第一反应者的意思是它想要变成这样
gets key events from the keyboard,
从键盘获取关键事件，
it's the first responder for key events.
它是关键事件的第一反应者。
You can make your UITextField start it cursor blinking and
你可以让你的UITextField开始它的光标闪烁
make the keyboard come up by sending it the message become
通过发送消息，让键盘弹出
first responder.
第一响应者。
If you tell your UITextField to become the first responder,
如果你告诉UITextField成为第一反应者，
the keyboard will appear, so
键盘会出现
that's how you make the keyboard up here.
这就是你在上面创建键盘的方法。
And similarly if you want the keyboard to go away and
类似的，如果你想让键盘消失
the blinking caret to go away, say resignFirstResponder
闪烁的汽车消失了，resignFirstResponder说
to the TextField that is the current first responder and
对于TextField，它是当前的第一反应者和
it will go away.
它将消失。
So that's how you control the keyboard.
这就是控制键盘的方法。
UITextField has a delegate.
UITextField委托。
It has about actually ten delegate methods.
它实际上有十种委托方法。
Can do quite a lot of interesting things.
可以做很多有趣的事情。
For example, when the keyboard comes up, most keyboards,
例如，当键盘出现，大多数键盘，
have a Return key in the lower right hand corner.
在右下角有一个返回键。
And when you hit that Return key,
当你点击返回键时，
you get this delegate method.
得到这个委托方法。
Text field show return, it returns a bool.
文本字段显示返回，返回一个bool。
It's basically saying,
基本上说,
should I do what I normally do when you press Return?
当你按下回车键时，我应该做我通常做的吗?
Because text fields are also controls,
因为文本字段也是控件，
they can do target action.
他们可以做目标动作。
So it's kind of asking you here,
所以这是在问你，
should I do target action today?
我今天应该做目标行动吗?
You know, some control dragged to an IBaction,
你知道，有些控制被拖到IBaction，
should I send that?
我应该发送吗?
It's what it's asking here what should I return.
它问的是我应该返回什么。
But one thing you can do and should return you might return
但有一件事你可以做，也应该回报你
yes, but you might also resignFirstResponder.
是的，但你也可以重新注册。
Because when it hits Return,
因为当它点击返回时，
you want the keyboard to go away.
你想要键盘消失。
Because otherwise the keyboard will not go away
否则键盘不会消失
when it hits Return.
当它到达回报。
Even if you have target action,
即使你有目标行动，
it's not gonna make that keyboard go away.
它不会让键盘消失。
It's very common that you wanna implement a text
你想要实现一个文本是很常见的
field delegate,
领域的委托,
just to make the keyboard go away when you hit Return.
只是为了让键盘在你点击返回时消失。
What other delegate methods does a TextField have?
TextField有哪些其他委托方法?
You can find out every time it resigns first responder.
你可以在每次resignfirstresponder的时候发现它。
It will send its delegate the method didEndEditing.
它将发送它的委托方法didEndEditing。
So this is a good way to find out, I'd better get the text
所以这是一个很好的发现方法，我最好还是把课文写出来
out of there and go do something with it.
离开那里，去做些事情。
Because someone hit Return, or
因为有人回车，或者
did something that caused resignFirstResponder to happen
有什么东西引起了resignFirstResponder的发生吗
so this method gets sent to you.
这个方法被发送给你。
In fact, this is probably a more common way to
事实上，这可能是更常见的方法
get the text out of a text field
从文本框中获取文本
then target/action is to implement its delegate.
然后目标/操作是实现它的委托。
And in end editing you get the text out of there.
最后编辑你会得到文本。
Or you could even grab it
或者你甚至可以抓住它
out of there in should return if you want.
如果你想要的话，可以从那里回来。
So text field is a control.
所以文本框是一个控件。
You can do target action, just Ctrl drag.
你可以做目标动作，按Ctrl拖动。
It has certain events that can cause target action to happen
它有某些事件可以导致目标动作发生
just like a button actually.
就像一个按钮。
And you can right click on a text field in a storyboard to
你可以右键点击故事板中的文本框
see what it can do there.
看看它能做什么。
The keyboard, you can change the kind of keyboard.
键盘，你可以改变键盘的种类。
The keyboard, for example, there's a keyboard for
键盘，比如，有一个键盘
entering URLs, and it's got a button on there, .com.
输入url，它在那里有一个按钮。
I think it even has a button, HTTP so
我想它甚至有一个按钮，HTTP
that you can quickly enter a URL.
你可以快速输入一个URL。
There's another URL which is like a phone dialer,
还有一个URL，像一个电话拨号器，
which is the keypad, or another, a keypad rather.
这是键盘，或者另一个，键盘。
It's like a phone dialer, so
它就像电话拨号器一样
it just has the numbers or whatever.
它只是有数字之类的。
So you can specify that.
你可以指定。
And the way you specify those things is you
你指定这些东西的方式就是你
don't send any messages to any keyboard object.
不要向任何键盘对象发送任何消息。
You send it to any object that is using the keyboard that
你把它发送给任何使用键盘的对象
implements the protocol UITextInputTraits.
实现了协议UITextInputTraits。
UITextInputTraits is a protocol that has
uitextinputtrait是一个具有的协议
all these things shown here in it and
所有这些都显示在它里面
when you send it to something like a text field
当你把它发送到文本框的时候
it configures its keyboard to match that.
它配置键盘来匹配它。
If you want auto correction in your text field,
如果你想在文本框中自动更正，
where you're typing and you're mistyping, and
你在打什么，你在哪里
it's autocorrecting as you go, you can get that.
它是自动修正的，你可以得到它。
Just set your auto correction type there to .yes in your
只需设置自动更正类型。是的在你
text field.
文本字段。
So you're sending these, these vars are on text field.
你发送这些，这些vars在文本框上。
But they're on text field because text field implements
但是它们在文本字段上，因为文本字段实现了
the UITextInputTraits protocol.
UITextInputTraits协议。
And you can do secure text for
你可以为它做安全的文本
passwords and all that kind of stuff.
密码之类的东西。
In other words, if you're looking to control your
换句话说，如果你想控制你的
keyboard, don't look in text field per se,
键盘，不要看文本框本身，
go look at this UITextInputTrait protocol, and
去看看这个UITextInputTrait协议
you'll see what you can do for your keyboard.
你会看到你能用键盘做什么。
You can also set an accessory view in your keyboard,
你也可以在你的键盘上设置一个附属视图，
a little view along the top of your keyboard that is just for
在你的键盘的顶部有一个小的视图
your app.
你的应用程序。
That's kind of fun.
这是一种乐趣。
You just, again,
你只是,
just TextInputTraits protocol thing.
只是TextInputTraits协议的事情。
One thing about the keyboard,
关于键盘，
I'm actually not gonna talk about this because of time.
我不会因为时间而讨论这个问题。
We'll talk about this in a later lecture.
我们稍后会讲到这个。
But the keyboard when it comes up it actually covers up
但当键盘出现的时候，它实际上会遮住
your views.
你的观点。
So you better make sure that text field is not underneath
所以最好确保文本字段不在下面
the keyboard.
键盘。
Otherwise keyboard will come up and
否则键盘会出现
people will not be able to type in your text.
人们将无法输入你的文本。
And I see a lot of final projects that do this,
我看到很多最终的项目，
where you have your nice UI and
你有好的UI和
you've got a lot of text fields on there.
这里有很多文本字段。
And you've got some text fields towards the bottom of
你有一些文本框在底部
the screen and when I try to run your app and do it and
当我试着运行你的应用程序并做它的时候
I click it, I am running it on a real device,
我点击它，我在一个真实的设备上运行它，
there's no keyboard I can't type in the simulator.
没有键盘，我不能在模拟器上打字。
One thing about when you're doing text field, be careful
当你在做文本字段时，要注意一点
because in the simulator you can just type on the keyboard.
因为在模拟器中，你可以在键盘上输入。
But in the real world the keyboard's gonna slide out
但在现实世界里，键盘会滑出
from the bottom.
从底部。
So students often will do their final projects do
所以学生通常会做最后的项目
the whole thing in the simulator.
在模拟器中。
They only barely do it on the device even though that's
他们只在设备上做，即使那是
absolutely required for your final project by the way.
顺便说一下，你的期末项目绝对需要。
And they turn it in and bam they get dinged pretty hard
他们把它打开，砰的一声，他们变得很硬
because I can't use their app.
因为我不能使用他们的应用。
Because this keyboard comes up and covers up the text fields
因为这个键盘出现并覆盖了文本字段
that they're wanting me to enter text into.
他们想让我输入文字。
The way you find out about the keyboard and
你了解键盘和键盘的方法
where it came over is using these observers.
它在哪里使用这些观察者。
And you're basically gonna observe the window, and
你基本上要观察窗户
the window is gonna send you this little notification that
窗口会发送给你这个小通知
says, hey, keyboard just came up, and in the notification
嘿，键盘刚刚出现，在通知中
that's sent to you, there's gonna be information
那是发给你的，会有信息的
about the rectangle that the keyboard used to cover you,
关于键盘用来覆盖你的矩形，
and you have to move your UI out of the way.
你必须把你的UI移开。
Hopefully you're in a scrollable thing like a table
希望你在一个可以滚动的东西里，像一张桌子
view or just a scroll view.
视图，或者只是一个滚动视图。
But if not then you just gotta move, set the frame of your
但如果不是这样，你就得动起来，设置好你的框架
super view or something to move that thing up.
超视图或其他东西来移动这个东西。
Because it's your responsibility to make sure
因为你有责任确保
that the keyboard is not covering something that's
键盘没有覆盖一些东西
necessarily to user UI.
一定要用户界面。
So when you're doing your final projects
所以当你在做最后的项目时
do it on a device.
在设备上做。
Otherwise you are very likely to run into this problem.
否则你很可能会遇到这个问题。
So we'll talk about these observers,
我们会谈到这些观察者，
these notification sender and stuff in a future lecture.
这些通知发送者和内容在未来的讲座中。
There's other text field properties not
还有其他文本字段属性不是
related to the keyboard, like it does the auto shrinking and
与键盘有关，就像它自动收缩和
all that stuff that we saw with UI labels so
我们在UI标签上看到的东西
you can control that stuff with text field.
你可以用文本框来控制这些东西。
I'll let you look at the doc to figure all that stuff out.
我会让你看医生把这些东西弄清楚。
Text fields also have a little right and left accessory view.
文本域也有一些右和左附属视图。
These little overviews for like a search button.
这些小的超视图就像一个搜索按钮。
Or little, you can put little exclamation points in there,
或者，你可以在里面放上感叹号，
things like that.
类似这样的事情。
So you can look for that as well.
所以你也可以找它。
That's it.
就是这样。
On Wednesday I'm gonna do TableView.
周三我要做TableView。
Big old lecture with a big old demo.
大旧的演讲，有一个大的旧demo。
And that's what your homework's gonna be about.
这就是你们的作业。
Friday, we have a section it's going to be on
周五，我们有一节课
CollectionView which I'd love to teach in main lecture
我想在主课上教的是CollectionView
because it's really an important class.
因为这是一个很重要的课程。
It's very much like TableView but more flexible,
它很像TableView，但更灵活，
a little more powerful than TableView.
比TableView更强大一些。
You kind of need to know TableView first,
你首先需要知道TableView，
that's why we do TableView on Wednesday and
这就是为什么我们在周三和
then the CollectionView on Friday.
然后是周五的CollectionView。
Then next week I'll be doing the object oriented database,
下周我会讲面向对象的数据库，
called Core Data, and you'll be integrating that into your
称为Core Data，你将把它集成到你的
assignment 4 to make your assignment 5.
任务4，让你的作业完成。
That's it, see you then.
就这样，到时候见。
>> For more please visit us at stanford.edu.
>> 更多课程详见 stanford.edu